[
  {
    "questionNum": 75001,
    "questionText": " How many electrons will have a charge of one coulomb?",
    "answerText": " 6.2 × 1018"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75002,
    "questionText": " 'The world is God and God is my soul' In which is the philosophy contained?",
    "answerText": " Upanishads"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75003,
    "questionText": " Which crop requires continuous semiaquatic condition for cultivation?",
    "answerText": " Rice"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75004,
    "questionText": " leaves used as wrappers for bides; from which are obtained?",
    "answerText": " Tendu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75005,
    "questionText": " Which Governor General is associated with Doctrine of Lapse?",
    "answerText": " Lord Dalhousie"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75006,
    "questionText": " What was the family of the Rigvedic Aryans?",
    "answerText": " Patriarchal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75007,
    "questionText": " In which transmission are sound and video signals transmitted simultaneously?",
    "answerText": " T.V. Transmission"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75008,
    "questionText": " How is the frequency of ultrasound wave typically?",
    "answerText": " Above 20;000 kHz"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75009,
    "questionText": " The highest annual precipitation occurs in which basin?",
    "answerText": " Amazon basin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75010,
    "questionText": " Which Mughal emperor prohibited the use of tobacco?",
    "answerText": " Jehangir"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75011,
    "questionText": " Who is credited with the invention of Algebra?",
    "answerText": " Aryabhatta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75012,
    "questionText": " How is the tax which is paid by the person on whom the tax is incident?",
    "answerText": " Direct tax"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75013,
    "questionText": " If the radius of blood vessels decrease; what will be in the blood pressur?",
    "answerText": " Increase"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75014,
    "questionText": " By which act was the office of the Secretary of State for India?",
    "answerText": " Government of India Act; 1858"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75015,
    "questionText": " Which is nuclear-capable submarine-launched ballistic missile?",
    "answerText": " Sagarika"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75016,
    "questionText": " ലോക ക്ഷയരോഗദിനം? ",
    "answerText": " മാർച്ച് 24 "
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75017,
    "questionText": " Who said; “God helps those who help themselves”?",
    "answerText": " Swami Vivekananda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75018,
    "questionText": " Which is associated with the formation of brown air in traffic congested cities?",
    "answerText": " Nitrogen oxide"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75019,
    "questionText": " In human beings; normally in which part; does the sperm fertilize the ovum?",
    "answerText": " Fallopian tube"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75020,
    "questionText": " Who were the first to attribute coins to the kings?",
    "answerText": " Indo Greeks"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75021,
    "questionText": " Silent valley having rare plant and animal is located in which state?",
    "answerText": " Kerala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75022,
    "questionText": " Which is used as the logo of the World Wide Fund for Nature (WWF)?",
    "answerText": " Panda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75023,
    "questionText": " BCG vaccination (Bacillus Calmette Guerine) is injected to get immunity from which disease?",
    "answerText": " Tuberculosis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75024,
    "questionText": " What structure is common to both earthworm and cockroach?",
    "answerText": " Ventral nerve cord"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75025,
    "questionText": " വൈറ്റ് പ്ളേഗ് എന്നറിയപ്പെടുന്നത്? ",
    "answerText": " ക്ഷയം "
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75026,
    "questionText": " Which State has no Panchayati Raj Institution at all?",
    "answerText": " Nagaland"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75027,
    "questionText": " Religious book of Parsis?",
    "answerText": " Zend Avesta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75028,
    "questionText": " Which metal is found in ‘plaster of paris’?",
    "answerText": " Calcium"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75029,
    "questionText": " Which element of Hinduism was practised in the Indus Valley Civilization?",
    "answerText": " Cult of Shiva"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75030,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Indian to win the World Amateur Billiards title?",
    "answerText": " Wilson Jones"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75031,
    "questionText": " International Day for the Abolition of Slavery; is observed on which date?",
    "answerText": " 2-Dec-2017"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75032,
    "questionText": " When did the British Govt. start ruling India directly?",
    "answerText": " After Sepoy Mutiny"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75033,
    "questionText": " Which is the second highest peak in the world?",
    "answerText": " K- (Godwin Austin)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75034,
    "questionText": " Which Strait which separates Asia from North America?",
    "answerText": " The Bering strait"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75035,
    "questionText": " What is Isomerism exhibited by acetic acid and methyl formate?",
    "answerText": " Functional group"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75036,
    "questionText": " Crusade for human rights is associated with which name?",
    "answerText": " Jimmy Carter"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75037,
    "questionText": " Who’ has been awarded the Sydney peace Prize 2012?",
    "answerText": " Sakai Holland"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75038,
    "questionText": " Who has the authority to remove the Vice-President from his office before the expiry of his term?",
    "answerText": " Parliament"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75039,
    "questionText": " Which is the lightest gas?",
    "answerText": " Hydrogen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75040,
    "questionText": " What is the poison of honey bee?",
    "answerText": " Acidic"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75041,
    "questionText": " When did the concept of pollution emerge clearly?",
    "answerText": " In the Post-Vedic period"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75042,
    "questionText": " Which animal lays eggs and does not produce young ones directly?",
    "answerText": " Echidna"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75043,
    "questionText": " Which colour types do not indicate fair or fine weather?",
    "answerText": " Cumulonimbus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75044,
    "questionText": " When was Lake Chad Basin Commission founded?",
    "answerText": " 22nd May; 1964"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75045,
    "questionText": " Where are Mulberry trees grown mainly for silk production in China?",
    "answerText": " Yangtze delta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75046,
    "questionText": " Which ruler at first assumed the title of ‘Hazrat-i-Ala’ and afterwards ‘Sultan’?",
    "answerText": " Sher Shah Suri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75047,
    "questionText": " ആയുർവേദത്തിൽ വിഷൂചിക എന്നറിയപ്പെടുന്നത്? ",
    "answerText": " കോളറ "
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75048,
    "questionText": " Which area is dominant in hunting and gathering?",
    "answerText": " Tropical forest"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75049,
    "questionText": " Which act aimed at providing a federal structure for India?",
    "answerText": " Government of India Act; 1935"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75050,
    "questionText": " By whom was first women’s university in India was founded?",
    "answerText": " Dhondo Keshave Karve"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75051,
    "questionText": " Pneumoconiosis affects the workers who work mainly in which industry?",
    "answerText": " Coal mining industry"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75052,
    "questionText": " Who was the second Portuguese Governor in India?",
    "answerText": " Alfonso de Albuquerque"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75053,
    "questionText": " Which is a World Bank group of five institutions?",
    "answerText": " IDA"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75054,
    "questionText": " What Minimum age is required to contest for Presidentship?",
    "answerText": " 35 years"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75055,
    "questionText": " Which is the first geostationary telecommunication satellite of India?",
    "answerText": " APPLE"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75056,
    "questionText": " Which was adopted from the Maurya dynasty in the emblem of Government of India?",
    "answerText": " Four lions"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75057,
    "questionText": " Who is the proponent and propagandist of the “Art of Living”?",
    "answerText": " Sri Sri Ravi Shankar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75058,
    "questionText": " Who was the Chola King to have conquered Bengal?",
    "answerText": " Rajendra I"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75059,
    "questionText": " Which elementis produced when concentrated cinnabar is roasted in the excess of air?",
    "answerText": " Hg"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75060,
    "questionText": " Which vitamin plays a vital role in the coagulating property of blood?",
    "answerText": " Vitamin K"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75061,
    "questionText": " By using which technique; is DNA fingerprint done?",
    "answerText": " Southern Blotting"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75062,
    "questionText": " Where was the Great Bath of the Indus Valley Civilization discovered?",
    "answerText": " Mohenjodaro"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75063,
    "questionText": " Which State of India has the largest reserves of monazite; with a high thorium content?",
    "answerText": " Kerala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75064,
    "questionText": " A lido is open air swimming pool where was the original lido?",
    "answerText": " Venice"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75065,
    "questionText": " Where was Shivaji crowned as an independent king?",
    "answerText": " Raigarh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75066,
    "questionText": " Where is Davos; the venue of the annual meeting of World Economic Forum; located?",
    "answerText": " Switzerland"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75067,
    "questionText": " ചതുപ്പ് രോഗം? ",
    "answerText": " മലേറിയ "
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75068,
    "questionText": " Which are the important raw materials required in cement industry?",
    "answerText": " Limestone and clay"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75069,
    "questionText": " Folding is the result of which force?",
    "answerText": " Orogenetic force"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75070,
    "questionText": " Gum Gopi Krishna was a maestro of which dance form?",
    "answerText": " Kathak"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75071,
    "questionText": " In which cell organelle do photo and thermochemical reactions occur in different sites?",
    "answerText": " Chloroplasts"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75072,
    "questionText": " What is Residual hill in the desert region?",
    "answerText": " Inselberg"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75073,
    "questionText": " Against which team did Virender Sehwag make his one day international debt?",
    "answerText": " Pakistan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75074,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Governor General of India?",
    "answerText": " Lord William Bentinck"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75075,
    "questionText": " By whom was the coin rupia first issued?",
    "answerText": " Sher Shah"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75076,
    "questionText": " By tradition; the famous lexicographer Amaraslmha was a contemporary of which poet?",
    "answerText": " Kalidasa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75077,
    "questionText": " Asteroids have their orbits between which planets?",
    "answerText": " Mars and Jupiter"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75078,
    "questionText": " Which country is the biggest producer of mango?",
    "answerText": " India"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75079,
    "questionText": " Which forms the largest share of deficit in Govt. of India budget?",
    "answerText": " Fiscal deficit"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75080,
    "questionText": " What is the process in which water is split during photosynthesis?",
    "answerText": " Photolysis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75081,
    "questionText": " Which area of water separates India from Sri Lanka?",
    "answerText": " Palk Strait"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75082,
    "questionText": " The ozone layer in the atmosphere is at a height of about how many k.m.?",
    "answerText": " 50 km"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75083,
    "questionText": " When was the monopoly of East India Company in trade brought under the control of the British Crown?",
    "answerText": " 1773 A.D."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75084,
    "questionText": " Which was a novelty in Shah Jahan’s buildings?",
    "answerText": " Makrana marble"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75085,
    "questionText": " How many feet in a fathom?",
    "answerText": " Six"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75086,
    "questionText": " Which ceil organelles function as the power house of a living cell?",
    "answerText": " Mitochondria"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75087,
    "questionText": " In which process; a nucleus spontaneously breaks down by emitting radiation?",
    "answerText": " Radioactive decay"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75088,
    "questionText": " Which pair belongs to the category of cold-blooded animals?",
    "answerText": " Frogs and snakes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75089,
    "questionText": " Which day is celebrated as ‘National Consumer Right Day?",
    "answerText": " 24th December"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75090,
    "questionText": " Who got noble prize for artificial synthesis of DNA?",
    "answerText": " Kornberg"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75091,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of the book ‘Preparing for the Twenty first Century’?",
    "answerText": " Paul Kennedy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75092,
    "questionText": " In a compound microscope; how is the intermediate image?",
    "answerText": " Real; inverted and magnified"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75093,
    "questionText": " When Raja Wodeyar founded the kingdom of Mysore; who was the ruler of the Vijayanagar Empire?",
    "answerText": " Ranga II"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75094,
    "questionText": " Which group of animals is primates?",
    "answerText": " Lemurs"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75095,
    "questionText": " In which year did the Peshwa became the official head of Maratha administration?",
    "answerText": " 1748 A.D."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75096,
    "questionText": " Who streamlined the Maratha administration after Shambhaji?",
    "answerText": " Raja Ram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75097,
    "questionText": " Which crop is grown in India mainly by dry farming?",
    "answerText": " Millet"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75098,
    "questionText": " When was the Rolling plan designed?",
    "answerText": " 1978-83"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75099,
    "questionText": " Which is the state that is top in the cultivation of flowers?",
    "answerText": " Tamil Nadu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75100,
    "questionText": " Which Gupta ruler was a poet and a musician and was adorned with the title of Kaviraja or King of poets?",
    "answerText": " Samudragupta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75101,
    "questionText": " What is the The chemical part of the dye that absorbs light and produces colour called?",
    "answerText": " A pigment"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75102,
    "questionText": " Who was the chairman of National Income Committee?",
    "answerText": " P. C. Mahalanobis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75103,
    "questionText": " Which was the South Indian state famous for its naval power?",
    "answerText": " Cholas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75104,
    "questionText": " Which bacteria helps in improving the soil fertility?",
    "answerText": " Rhizobrum"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75105,
    "questionText": " The oldest monarchy in the world is that of which country?",
    "answerText": " Japan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75106,
    "questionText": " Who translated Ramayana into Persian?",
    "answerText": " Badaurii"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75107,
    "questionText": " By which the maximum amount of energy in the present day world is provided?",
    "answerText": " Coal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75108,
    "questionText": " A convex lens of glass has power P in air. If it is immersed in water; what will be its power?",
    "answerText": " Less than P"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75109,
    "questionText": " Which dynasty's founder was an elected king?",
    "answerText": " Pala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75110,
    "questionText": " From where is the term ‘sufi’ derived?",
    "answerText": " From a type of garment"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75111,
    "questionText": " Which was the first fort which the British constructed in India?",
    "answerText": " St. George Fort"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75112,
    "questionText": " The Himalayas are formed of parallel fold ranges of which the oldest range?",
    "answerText": " The Great Himalayan Range"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75113,
    "questionText": " Which is at the apex of the-three tier system of Panchayati Raj?",
    "answerText": " Zila Parishad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75114,
    "questionText": " The powers of the Election Commission are given in which Article of the Constitution?",
    "answerText": 324
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75115,
    "questionText": " Which is an inland drainage area?",
    "answerText": " Rann of Kutch"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75116,
    "questionText": " In electric supply lines in India; which parameter is kept constant?",
    "answerText": " Frequency"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75117,
    "questionText": " Tasseomancy is fortune telling using what?",
    "answerText": " Tea Leaves"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75118,
    "questionText": " In which year did Mahatma Gandhi return to India; leaving South Africa for ever?",
    "answerText": 1915
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75119,
    "questionText": " What is a baby rabbit called?",
    "answerText": " Kit or Kitten"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75120,
    "questionText": " Which cup/trophy is associated with football?",
    "answerText": " Santosh Trophy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75121,
    "questionText": " What is the more common name of Sildenafil Citrate?",
    "answerText": " Viagra"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75122,
    "questionText": " The Maratha kingdom was founded by Shivaji during which reign?",
    "answerText": " Aurangzeb I"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75123,
    "questionText": " Before Delhi; where was the capital of India during the British India?",
    "answerText": " Calcutta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75124,
    "questionText": " What is an example of Miscelles System here?",
    "answerText": " Soap + Water"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75125,
    "questionText": " Which Philosophy holds that the world is created and maintained by Universal Law?",
    "answerText": " Jain Philosophy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75126,
    "questionText": " Maoris are the inhabitants of which country?",
    "answerText": " New Zealand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75127,
    "questionText": " In which city does World’s highest urban density of population occurs?",
    "answerText": " Tokyo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75128,
    "questionText": " Which biologist; proposed that life is originated in water;?",
    "answerText": " Thales"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75129,
    "questionText": " Which pair of metals- are supposed to constitute the internal core of the earth?",
    "answerText": " Nickel and Iron"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75130,
    "questionText": " What is the first large research reactor of India that uses U-233 as fuel?",
    "answerText": " KAMINI1"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75131,
    "questionText": " One the banks of which. river were Alexander and Porus involved in a grim battle?",
    "answerText": " Jhelum"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75132,
    "questionText": " What is the upper part of the mantle upon which the crust of the Earth floats called?",
    "answerText": " Asthenosphere"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75133,
    "questionText": " Which is ‘the largest island?",
    "answerText": " Kalatdeitnunat"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75134,
    "questionText": " Who was the leader of the Young Bengal Movement?",
    "answerText": " Henry Vivian Derozio"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75135,
    "questionText": " Who was the Viceroy of India at the time of Jallianwala Bagh Massacre?",
    "answerText": " Lord Chelmsford"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75136,
    "questionText": " Who rode a horse called Bucephalus?",
    "answerText": " Alexander the Great"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75137,
    "questionText": " Who has written the book ‘My Frozen Turbulence in Kashmire’?",
    "answerText": " Jagmohan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75138,
    "questionText": " Which synthetic fibre is known as artificial silk?",
    "answerText": " Rayon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75139,
    "questionText": " Which organ of UNO is considered as world parliament?",
    "answerText": " General Assembly"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75140,
    "questionText": " Which country stood second in the 1992 Barcelona Olympics medal tally?",
    "answerText": " US"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75141,
    "questionText": " Which organ have the capacity of regeneration?",
    "answerText": " Liver"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75142,
    "questionText": " Blue litmus paper is converted into red in solution of which thing?",
    "answerText": " acid"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75143,
    "questionText": " Amarya Sen; the NRI Nobel laureate got the honour for which work?",
    "answerText": " Poverty and famines"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75144,
    "questionText": " In which plan was the objective of self-reliance and zero net foreign aid declared?",
    "answerText": " Fourth -Yr Plan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75145,
    "questionText": " From which ruler did Humayun received the Kohinoor diamond?",
    "answerText": " The Ruler of Gwalior"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75146,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Indian to be honoured with a lifetime achievement Oscar Award?",
    "answerText": " Satyajit Roy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75147,
    "questionText": " We cannot see during a fog. why?",
    "answerText": " Because of scattering of light"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75148,
    "questionText": " Who is entitled to initiate a Bill for Constitutional Amendments?",
    "answerText": " Either House of Parliament"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75149,
    "questionText": " The light coming from stars gives the idea of their which quality?",
    "answerText": " Temperature"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75150,
    "questionText": " Which was initially the most powerful city state of Indian in the 6th century B. C.?",
    "answerText": " Magadh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75151,
    "questionText": " Which is the source of information about early Vedic period?",
    "answerText": " Rigveda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75152,
    "questionText": " Where did the first nuclear explosion in India take place?",
    "answerText": " Pokhran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75153,
    "questionText": " The ‘Uruguay Round’ negotiations resulted in the establishment of which organization?",
    "answerText": " WTO"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75154,
    "questionText": " When International Day of Older Persons; recognized by the UN is observed?",
    "answerText": " 1-Oct-2017"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75155,
    "questionText": " Which is a high cloud?",
    "answerText": " Cirrus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75156,
    "questionText": " Amerigo Vespucci airport is in which city?",
    "answerText": " Florence"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75157,
    "questionText": " Which hydrocarbon is mainly present in gobar gas?",
    "answerText": " Methane"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75158,
    "questionText": " Who has been called the 'Napoleon of India'?",
    "answerText": " Samudragupta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75159,
    "questionText": " The Governor General of Fort William became the Governor General of India under which Charter Act?– ?",
    "answerText": 1833
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75160,
    "questionText": " Where is Peaty soil found?",
    "answerText": " Kerala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75161,
    "questionText": " By whom are the portfolios allocated to the ministers?",
    "answerText": " The Prime Minister"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75162,
    "questionText": " Which amendments accorded precedence to Directive Principle over Fundamental Rights?",
    "answerText": " 42nd Amendment"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75163,
    "questionText": " Which acid is used in synthetic lemonade?",
    "answerText": " Citric acid"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75164,
    "questionText": " Why are Clear nights colder than cloudy nights?",
    "answerText": " Because of Radiation"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75165,
    "questionText": " Who was the first ‘Indian to swim across English Channel?",
    "answerText": " Mihir Sen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75166,
    "questionText": " Which is the highest and final judicial tribunal in respect of the Constitution of India?",
    "answerText": " Supreme Court"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75167,
    "questionText": " The United Nations declared 2014 as which International Year?",
    "answerText": " Crystallography"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75168,
    "questionText": " Which is the main ingredient in cement?",
    "answerText": " Lime stone"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75169,
    "questionText": " Quick Mail Service was started in?",
    "answerText": 1975
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75170,
    "questionText": " Which is the tax that takes away a higher proportion of one’s income as the income rises?",
    "answerText": " Progressive tax"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75171,
    "questionText": " Which physical quantities have the same dimensions?",
    "answerText": " Momentum and impulse"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75172,
    "questionText": " Where were the xxvii (1996) Summer Olympic games were held?",
    "answerText": " Atlanta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75173,
    "questionText": " Which inscription describes the achievements of Kharavela; king of Kalinga?",
    "answerText": " Hathigunipha inscription"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75174,
    "questionText": " What is an example of vestigial organ in man?",
    "answerText": " Canine teeth"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75175,
    "questionText": " What is the natural source of hydrocarbon?",
    "answerText": " Biomass"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75176,
    "questionText": " By whom was Artificial gene synthesis first done in laboratory?",
    "answerText": " Khurana"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75177,
    "questionText": " Who set up the Atmiya Sabha in Kolkata in the first half of the nineteenth century?",
    "answerText": " Ram Mohan Roy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75178,
    "questionText": " Inside the body; why does blood not coagulate?",
    "answerText": " Due to the presence of heparin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75179,
    "questionText": " When is the world biodiversity day celebrated annually?",
    "answerText": " 5th June"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75180,
    "questionText": " The Bahmanis of the Deccan rose to prominence in which century?",
    "answerText": " 14th century"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75181,
    "questionText": " Who was the Chairman of the Drafting Committee of the Indian Constitution?",
    "answerText": " B. R. Ambedkar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75182,
    "questionText": " Who is often described as the second 'Parasurama' or the exterminator of the entire kshatriya race?",
    "answerText": " Mahapadrna"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75183,
    "questionText": " Which glass is used in bullet proof screens?",
    "answerText": " Reinforced glass"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75184,
    "questionText": " What is the main source of revenue to meet different expenditures?",
    "answerText": " Internal borrowings"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75185,
    "questionText": " Which two countries follow China and India in the decreasing order of their populations?",
    "answerText": " USA and Indonesia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75186,
    "questionText": " In which Molecule the distance between two adjacent carbon atoms is longest?",
    "answerText": " Ethane"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75187,
    "questionText": " What is the period of one revolution of sun around the centre of galaxy called?",
    "answerText": " Cosmic year"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75188,
    "questionText": " What is the ideal average NPK ratio aggregated for the country as a whole?",
    "answerText": 0.16806713
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75189,
    "questionText": " Which Very strong and cold icy winds that blow in the Polar regions?",
    "answerText": " Blizzards"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75190,
    "questionText": " Which is the most southerly test match grounds of England?",
    "answerText": " The Lords"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75191,
    "questionText": " To whom does the Public Accounts Committee submit its report?",
    "answerText": " The Speaker of the Lok Sabha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75192,
    "questionText": " If a solar eclipse occurs when the moon is quite far from the earth; how would be the eclipse?",
    "answerText": " Likely to be annular"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75193,
    "questionText": " The island of Honshu is located in which country?",
    "answerText": " Japan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75194,
    "questionText": " Name the first war submarine invented by David Bushnell?",
    "answerText": " Turtle"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75195,
    "questionText": " In a p-type semiconductor; Which are the majority charge carriers?",
    "answerText": " Holes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75196,
    "questionText": " ‘Padmavat’ of Malik Muhammad Jaisi; a notable; work in Hindi; was completed during which reign?",
    "answerText": " Sher Shah"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75197,
    "questionText": " During rainy seasons why do doors made up of wood swell up?",
    "answerText": " Due to imbibition"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75198,
    "questionText": " The celebrated novel ‘The Godfather’ was authored by which author?",
    "answerText": " Mario Puzo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75199,
    "questionText": " Who is to conduct the elections to the Panchayats and Municipalities?",
    "answerText": " State Election Commission"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75200,
    "questionText": " Which was the first scholar; who read Ashokan edicts?",
    "answerText": " James Princep"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75201,
    "questionText": " Which gulf would have to be crossed to reach Sri Lanka from Nagercoil?",
    "answerText": " Gulf of Mannar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75202,
    "questionText": " Which Bhakti saint wrote the commentary on Vedanta sutras in Sanskrit?",
    "answerText": " Vallabhacharya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75203,
    "questionText": " Who invented the technique of extracting scent from Rose?",
    "answerText": " Nurjahan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75204,
    "questionText": " Jude Felix has established reputation as an Indian player in which game?",
    "answerText": " Hockey"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75205,
    "questionText": " Whose philosophy is called the Advaita?",
    "answerText": " Shankaracharya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75206,
    "questionText": " In which country was the 2010 Football World Cup held?",
    "answerText": " South Africa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75207,
    "questionText": " What is the cause of Exposure of rock to the changes of temperature?",
    "answerText": " Mechanical weathering"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75208,
    "questionText": " When is World Humanitarian Action Day is observed?",
    "answerText": " 8-Oct-2017"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75209,
    "questionText": " Book of poems entitled ‘Lamhe Lamhe’ is written by which Indian actress?",
    "answerText": " Deepti Naval"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75210,
    "questionText": " The Westminster is the oldest and biggest what in the USA?",
    "answerText": " Dog Show"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75211,
    "questionText": " Which is purest form of iron?",
    "answerText": " Wrought iron"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75212,
    "questionText": " Indian Institute of Forest management is located at which place?",
    "answerText": " Dehradun"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75213,
    "questionText": " Which is used to remove astigmatism for a human eye?",
    "answerText": " Cylindrical lens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75214,
    "questionText": " Which one of the Chola kings conquered Ceylon (Sinhal) first?",
    "answerText": " Rajaraja I"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75215,
    "questionText": " In which Indian state is the game of Polo said to have originated?",
    "answerText": " Manipur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75216,
    "questionText": " When was petroleum discovered first in commercial quantities in India?",
    "answerText": 1890
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75217,
    "questionText": " Which saint wrote ‘Bijak’?",
    "answerText": " Kabir"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75218,
    "questionText": " Who was the author of the famous work All Contributions to the Critic of Political Economy’?",
    "answerText": " Karl Marx"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75219,
    "questionText": " When was National Development Council set up?",
    "answerText": 1952
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75220,
    "questionText": " Which organ cannot be transplanted?",
    "answerText": " Brain"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75221,
    "questionText": " In an atom the order of filling up of the orbitals is governed by which principle?",
    "answerText": " Aufbau principle"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75222,
    "questionText": " Independent alternation of generation is found in which plant?",
    "answerText": " Fern"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75223,
    "questionText": " In which country is ‘Takla Makan’ desert situated?",
    "answerText": " China"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75224,
    "questionText": " Who usurped the throne of Magadlia in 322 B. C.?",
    "answerText": " Chandragupta Maurya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75225,
    "questionText": " Who were considered constitutionalist within the Indian National Congress?",
    "answerText": " Satyamurty and K. M. Munshi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75226,
    "questionText": " Which enzyme is found in human saliva?",
    "answerText": " Ptyalin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75227,
    "questionText": " What happens when a sudden fall in the barometric reading?",
    "answerText": " Storm"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75228,
    "questionText": " Under which Ministry of the Government of India does the Food and Nutrition Board work?",
    "answerText": " Ministry of Agriculture"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75229,
    "questionText": " What will be the antipodal position of a place located at 350 south and 800 west?",
    "answerText": " 350 north and 1000 east"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75230,
    "questionText": " Which radiation carries maximum energy?",
    "answerText": " Gamma-rays"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75231,
    "questionText": " The highest temperature is achieved in which type furnance?",
    "answerText": " Electric"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75232,
    "questionText": " When Metal carbonate reacts with dilute acids; what does it forms?",
    "answerText": " CO2"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75233,
    "questionText": " Who is responsible for the collection and publication of monetary and financial information?",
    "answerText": " Reserve Bank of India"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75234,
    "questionText": " In which case is the area under cultivation is declining fast?",
    "answerText": " Jute"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75235,
    "questionText": " Which country has the briefest Constitution in the world?",
    "answerText": " USA"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75236,
    "questionText": " Enlargment of which gland takes place due to deficiency of iodine?",
    "answerText": " Thyroid"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75237,
    "questionText": " Which techniqu was introduced by the Turks in the textile sector in India?",
    "answerText": " Spinning wheel"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75238,
    "questionText": " Vasco da Gama discovered the sea-route to India in which year?",
    "answerText": 1498
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75239,
    "questionText": " Where are Grasses almost absent?",
    "answerText": " In tropical wet-evergreen forest"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75240,
    "questionText": " Old Dominion was a nickname of which US state?",
    "answerText": " Virginia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75241,
    "questionText": " Why do Electricians use rubber gloves while working?",
    "answerText": " Rubber is an insulator"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75242,
    "questionText": " What is the name for the group of men who elect a Pope?",
    "answerText": " College of Cardinals"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75243,
    "questionText": " Which is not an important factor of climate of an area?",
    "answerText": " Longitude"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75244,
    "questionText": " The northern part of the west coast is known by which name?",
    "answerText": " Konkan coast"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75245,
    "questionText": " If the angle between two plane mirrors is 60°; then how many number of image will be formed?",
    "answerText": 5
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75246,
    "questionText": " Which is the longest mountain range in the world?",
    "answerText": " Andes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75247,
    "questionText": " Who was the first lady Governor of an Indian state?",
    "answerText": " Mrs. Sarojini Naidu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75248,
    "questionText": " A House for Mr. Biswas is a book authored by?",
    "answerText": " V.S. Naipaul"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75249,
    "questionText": " Which is the oldest monument?",
    "answerText": " Ajanta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75250,
    "questionText": " In which year; UN General Assembly terminated South Africa’s mandate over Namibia?",
    "answerText": 1966
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75251,
    "questionText": " The time of Cairo is hours ahead of Greenwich time. Cairo is situated at which degree?",
    "answerText": " 30° East"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75252,
    "questionText": " Where is the Taiga belt found?",
    "answerText": " Temperate grasslands and Tundra"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75253,
    "questionText": " In which year Akbar assumed actual control over the administration of his empire?",
    "answerText": 1560
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75254,
    "questionText": " ‘Higher than Hopes’ is a biography of which author?",
    "answerText": " Nelson Mandela"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75255,
    "questionText": " Which gas comes out during photosynthesis?",
    "answerText": " Oxygen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75256,
    "questionText": " Which gland is responsible for the secretion of insulin?",
    "answerText": " Pancrease"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75257,
    "questionText": " In which year were the first general elections in India held?",
    "answerText": 1951
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75258,
    "questionText": " What is formed when white phosphorus is heated at 540 K in the absence of air?",
    "answerText": " Red phosphorus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75259,
    "questionText": " What is an intrusion of magma along a bedding plane is called?",
    "answerText": " Batholith"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75260,
    "questionText": " Who wrote Les Miserable?",
    "answerText": " Victor Hugo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75261,
    "questionText": " Bimbavati Devi is a well-known dancer of which type of dance?",
    "answerText": " Manipuri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75262,
    "questionText": " What is the number of puranas?",
    "answerText": 18
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75263,
    "questionText": " What does Talc contains?",
    "answerText": " Magnesium; silicon and oxygen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75264,
    "questionText": " The first railway line was laid in which state?",
    "answerText": " North-East England"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75265,
    "questionText": " Which type of volcanic eruptions is not usually exposive?",
    "answerText": " Hawaiian"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75266,
    "questionText": " By whom was the law of constant proportions enunciated?",
    "answerText": " Proust"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75267,
    "questionText": " Shovna Narayan is a reputed personality in which field?",
    "answerText": " Classical dance"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75268,
    "questionText": " What is the first compound which is fixed during photosynthesis?",
    "answerText": " Glucose"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75269,
    "questionText": " Which is the gas used to extinguish fire?",
    "answerText": " Carbon dioxide"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75270,
    "questionText": " In Greek mythology Deianeira was the wife of who?",
    "answerText": " Hercules"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75271,
    "questionText": " What do Quantitative credit controls not include?",
    "answerText": " RBI directives"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75272,
    "questionText": " What is the only creature born with horns?",
    "answerText": " Giraffe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75273,
    "questionText": " Vatapi was the capital of the which reign?",
    "answerText": " Chalukyas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75274,
    "questionText": " Akbar founded his own religion known as ‘Din-i-Ilahi’ what was its mean?",
    "answerText": " Divine faith"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75275,
    "questionText": " Which instrument used to measure the force and velocity of the wind?",
    "answerText": " Anemometer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75276,
    "questionText": " If you had pogonophobia what would you be afraid of?",
    "answerText": " Beards"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75277,
    "questionText": " At the time of short-circuit; what will be the current in the circuit?",
    "answerText": " Increases heavily"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75278,
    "questionText": " Vikramshila Mahavihara was established by the ruler of which dyanasy?",
    "answerText": " Pala Dynasty"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75279,
    "questionText": " According to whom was persecutor of Buddhism?",
    "answerText": " Divyavadana"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75280,
    "questionText": " Indira Gandhi International Airport at?",
    "answerText": " New Delhi."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75281,
    "questionText": " By which would Desert plants be characterised?",
    "answerText": " By sunken stomata"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75282,
    "questionText": " Who created the unforgettable literary character ‘Swami’?",
    "answerText": " R. K. Narayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75283,
    "questionText": " The United Nations declared 4th week of September which week?",
    "answerText": " Peace Week"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75284,
    "questionText": " Which Strait separates Asia from North America?",
    "answerText": " The Bering Strait"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75285,
    "questionText": " The Chief Minister of Union Territory where such a set up exists; is appointed by whom?",
    "answerText": " Lt. Governor"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75286,
    "questionText": " How much portion of egg does protein content?",
    "answerText": 0.133
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75287,
    "questionText": " Which climatic factor which has the least effect upon a terrestrial ecosystem?",
    "answerText": " Wind"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75288,
    "questionText": " Which compound caused tragedy of Bhopal in 1984?",
    "answerText": " Methyl isocynate"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75289,
    "questionText": " By which Carbon and hydrogen are estimated in organic compounds?",
    "answerText": " Liebig’s method"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75290,
    "questionText": " Who received Nobel Prize twice for the same subject?",
    "answerText": " Marie Curie"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75291,
    "questionText": " Which type of experiment has the maximum spatial scale?",
    "answerText": " Natural experiment"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75292,
    "questionText": " Who was appointed by Ashoka to administer justice in his empire?",
    "answerText": " Rajuka"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75293,
    "questionText": " Under which act was the Supreme Court set up?",
    "answerText": " Regulating Act"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75294,
    "questionText": " Which modification of root does not store food?",
    "answerText": " Stilt"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75295,
    "questionText": " Who was the first lady to preside over the Congress?",
    "answerText": " Annie Besant"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75296,
    "questionText": " National Environmental Engineering Research Institute is located at which city?",
    "answerText": " Nagpur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75297,
    "questionText": " On which thing Erosion of soil by a river mainly depends?",
    "answerText": " Its speed at which it flows"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75298,
    "questionText": " Who is considered to be the greatest of all times?",
    "answerText": " Charles Dickens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75299,
    "questionText": " How much does one degree of the circumference of the earth measure (approx.)?",
    "answerText": " 111 km"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75300,
    "questionText": " At where were the High Courts in India first started?",
    "answerText": " Bombay; Madras; Calcutta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75301,
    "questionText": " Of which metal was the The famous figure of a dancing girl found in the excavations of Harappa?",
    "answerText": " Bronze"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75302,
    "questionText": " What is the percentage of radiant energy reflected back by surface called?",
    "answerText": " Albedo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75303,
    "questionText": " The rock-cut temples of Mahabalipuram were built under the patronage of which king?",
    "answerText": " Pallava kings"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75304,
    "questionText": " Under which act was the Supreme Court in British India established?",
    "answerText": " Regulating Act of 1773"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75305,
    "questionText": " Which gland disapear during old age?",
    "answerText": " Thymus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75306,
    "questionText": " If a liquid wets a solid surface; what is the angle of contact?",
    "answerText": " Less than 90°"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75307,
    "questionText": " Which sites of Harappan are not in India?",
    "answerText": " Mohenjodaro and Harappa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75308,
    "questionText": " Under which article was the State of Jammu and Kashmir accorded special status?",
    "answerText": " Article 370 of the Constitution"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75309,
    "questionText": " Which can be used for biological control of mosquitoes?",
    "answerText": " Gambusia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75310,
    "questionText": " What does National income ignore?",
    "answerText": " Salary of employees"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75311,
    "questionText": " Which group of people changes their house types according to seasons?",
    "answerText": " Kirghiz"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75312,
    "questionText": " In methane molecule how are the four hydrogen atoms arranged?",
    "answerText": " As tetrahedral"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75313,
    "questionText": " A typical human ribcage consists of how many ribs?",
    "answerText": 24
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75314,
    "questionText": " Which country has the largest forest area in the world?",
    "answerText": " Russian Federation"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75315,
    "questionText": " The term L.B.W. is associated with which game?",
    "answerText": " Cricket"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75316,
    "questionText": " On April 16; 1853 first train in India was opened between Bombay and Thana covering a distance of?",
    "answerText": " 34 km."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75317,
    "questionText": " Total internal reflection of light is possible when light enters from which thing?",
    "answerText": " Water to air"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75318,
    "questionText": " Which river is known as India’s River of Sorrow?",
    "answerText": " Kosi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75319,
    "questionText": " Edward Jenner is related with which disease?",
    "answerText": " Small pox"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75320,
    "questionText": " What was the real name of Tantiya Tope?",
    "answerText": " Ramchandra Pandurang"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75321,
    "questionText": " Railways is a subject on which list?",
    "answerText": " Union List"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75322,
    "questionText": " Which city has the longest day in the month of June?",
    "answerText": " Kolkata"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75323,
    "questionText": " Dhondu Pant is better known as which name?",
    "answerText": " Nana Saheb"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75324,
    "questionText": " Who is the ‘author of the book ‘A Brief History of Time’?",
    "answerText": " Stephen Hawking"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75325,
    "questionText": " S. Vijaya Lakshmi and Nisha Mohita are associated with which game?",
    "answerText": " Chess"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75326,
    "questionText": " Which is the latest addition to the list of UNESCO’s world heritage sites in India?",
    "answerText": " Red Fort"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75327,
    "questionText": " Which Indian was honoured by the World Statesman Award; 2012?",
    "answerText": " Stephen Harper"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75328,
    "questionText": " The term nishka; which meant an ornament in the Vedic period; was used in later tirmes; what did it denote?",
    "answerText": " A coin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75329,
    "questionText": " In which period did iron come to be used by the Vedic people?",
    "answerText": " In around 1000 B.C"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75330,
    "questionText": " Which chemical is used in foam fire extinguishers?",
    "answerText": " Aluminium sulphate"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75331,
    "questionText": " Which are the leading states in the production of cotton in India?",
    "answerText": " Maharashtra and Gujarat"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75332,
    "questionText": " What is the distance of the equator from either of the poles?",
    "answerText": " 10;002 km"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75333,
    "questionText": " Which type of the fruit formed without fertilisation?",
    "answerText": " Parthenocarpy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75334,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of the book ‘My other two daughters’?",
    "answerText": " Surjit Singh Barnala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75335,
    "questionText": " Why does diffusion of light in the atmosphere take place?",
    "answerText": " Due to dust particles"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75336,
    "questionText": " Which is electrical circuits used to get smooth de output from a rectified circuit called?",
    "answerText": " Filter"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75337,
    "questionText": " Which Indian port leads in imports?",
    "answerText": " Mumbai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75338,
    "questionText": " What is the number of unpaired electrons in carbon atom?",
    "answerText": 2
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75339,
    "questionText": " A substance; when inserted between the poles of a magnet; is pushed out; what is it?",
    "answerText": " Diamagnetic"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75340,
    "questionText": " On which day is the budget; in normal circumstances; presented to the Parliament?",
    "answerText": " The last day of February"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75341,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of the classic book Life Divine?",
    "answerText": " Aurobindo Ghosh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75342,
    "questionText": " Who gave the first experimental value of G?",
    "answerText": " Cavendish"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75343,
    "questionText": " Which is the chief characteristics of wet and dry tropics?",
    "answerText": " Constant heating"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75344,
    "questionText": " Where is the headquarters of the International Telecommunications Union?",
    "answerText": " Geneva"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75345,
    "questionText": " What is richest source of vitamin D is?",
    "answerText": " Cod liver oil"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75346,
    "questionText": " For which snake is the diet mainly composed of other snakes?",
    "answerText": " King cobra"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75347,
    "questionText": " Which is the country with the highest density of population in Europe?",
    "answerText": " Netherlands"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75348,
    "questionText": " Which was the Mughal emperor; who died to a’ sudden fall from the staircase;?",
    "answerText": " Humayun"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75349,
    "questionText": " Chris Even’s name is associated with which sport?",
    "answerText": " Tennis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75350,
    "questionText": " Who were the first to issue gold coins?",
    "answerText": " Indo Greeks"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75351,
    "questionText": " Which planet of the solar system spins on its axis at the fastest rate?",
    "answerText": " Jupiter"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75352,
    "questionText": " By which act did the Crown take the Government of India into its own hands?",
    "answerText": " Government of India Act; 1858"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75353,
    "questionText": " How many orangutans disappear each year as result of palm oil farming?",
    "answerText": 5000
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75354,
    "questionText": " Which is a mixed fertiliser?",
    "answerText": " NPK"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75355,
    "questionText": " The equator cuts through which island?",
    "answerText": " Borneo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75356,
    "questionText": " Which country is land locked?",
    "answerText": " Bolivia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75357,
    "questionText": " When does World Health Organization organise ‘World Aids Day’?",
    "answerText": " 1st December"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75358,
    "questionText": " Rabindranath Tagore was awarded Noble Prize for his which literary work?",
    "answerText": " Geetanjali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75359,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Indian ruler to organise Haj pilgrimage at the expense of the state?",
    "answerText": " Akbar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75360,
    "questionText": " Which Indian batsman was the first to hit 44 fours in a test match innings?",
    "answerText": " Laxman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75361,
    "questionText": " For which landform is Colorado in U.S.A. famous?",
    "answerText": " Grand Canyon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75362,
    "questionText": " Which physical quantities do not have same dimensions?",
    "answerText": " Force and Pressure"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75363,
    "questionText": " Human protein x – antitrysin is used for which disease?",
    "answerText": " Emphysama"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75364,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Englishman to preside over a Congress session?",
    "answerText": " George Yule"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75365,
    "questionText": " Which is the membrane that protects the developing embryo from desication?",
    "answerText": " Amnion"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75366,
    "questionText": " When sodium bicarbonate is heated; what is the product obtained?",
    "answerText": " Na2 CO3"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75367,
    "questionText": " If a proton of mass m is moving with the velocity of light; what will its mass be?",
    "answerText": " Infinite"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75368,
    "questionText": " Which is a type of planetary wind?",
    "answerText": " Westerlies"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75369,
    "questionText": " By whom was the book Wealth of Nations’ written?",
    "answerText": " Adam Smith"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75370,
    "questionText": " When the East India Company came into existence; By whom was England was ruled?",
    "answerText": " Tudors"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75371,
    "questionText": " The executive power is vested in the President but on whose advice is it actually used?",
    "answerText": " The Council of Ministers"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75372,
    "questionText": " Bronze coins of Nataraja cast during the Chola period invariably show the deity with how many hands?",
    "answerText": " Four hands"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75373,
    "questionText": " What is the mean of Ad Valorem?",
    "answerText": " According to value"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75374,
    "questionText": " In which culture is the earliest evidence of silver in India found?",
    "answerText": " Harappan Culture"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75375,
    "questionText": " Where is Pakistan’s nuclear power plant located?",
    "answerText": " Kahuta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75376,
    "questionText": " What is the SI unit of Young’s modulus of elasticity?",
    "answerText": " Newton/m2"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75377,
    "questionText": " Which is the most malleable metal?",
    "answerText": " Gold"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75378,
    "questionText": " Where is the headquarters of World Health Organization?",
    "answerText": " Geneva; Switzerland"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75379,
    "questionText": " Which author won the Booker Prize twice?",
    "answerText": " J.M. Coetzee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75380,
    "questionText": " Companion cells are usually seen associated with which tube?",
    "answerText": " Sieve tube"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75381,
    "questionText": " Which river emerges from Amarkantak plateau in Madhya Pradesh?",
    "answerText": " Narmada"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75382,
    "questionText": " Bhakt Tukaram was a contemporary of which Mughal emperor?",
    "answerText": " Jahangir"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75383,
    "questionText": " Mesons are found in which rays?",
    "answerText": " Cosmic rays"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75384,
    "questionText": " Chromosomes are made up of which main component?",
    "answerText": " DNA"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75385,
    "questionText": " Which is called ‘The Bible of Tamil Land’?",
    "answerText": " Kural"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75386,
    "questionText": " What creature is the symbol of medicine?",
    "answerText": " Snake"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75387,
    "questionText": " ‘Darwin finches’ refers to a group of which creatrue?",
    "answerText": " Birds"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75388,
    "questionText": " Ancient Monuments Preservation Act was passed during which Viceroyality?",
    "answerText": " Curzon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75389,
    "questionText": " Which tissue in man where no cell division; occurs after birth?",
    "answerText": " Nerves"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75390,
    "questionText": " Jawaharlal Nehru Airport (Santa-Cruz) is at?",
    "answerText": " Mumbai."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75391,
    "questionText": " How many PIN CODE Zone divided in the country?",
    "answerText": 8
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75392,
    "questionText": " Which type of coal is difficult to light in the open air?",
    "answerText": " Peat"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75393,
    "questionText": " Escape Velocity from the earth is?:?",
    "answerText": " 11 Km per Sec."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75394,
    "questionText": " What is the main activity of Eskimos during the short period of summer season?",
    "answerText": " Hunting"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75395,
    "questionText": " Of which influence does the sculptures of the Gandhara school reflect?",
    "answerText": " Greeks"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75396,
    "questionText": " Which is an active component of oil of clove?",
    "answerText": " Eugenol"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75397,
    "questionText": " After textiles; which is India’s second important industry?",
    "answerText": " Iron and steel"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75398,
    "questionText": " Which kind of organisms are the diatoms?",
    "answerText": " Unicellular algae"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75399,
    "questionText": " Where was the first state-owned fertilizer plant set-up in 1951?",
    "answerText": " Sindri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75400,
    "questionText": " Which are the Continents that form a mirror image of each other?",
    "answerText": " Africa and South America"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75401,
    "questionText": " What is the maximum strength of the nominated members in both the Houses of Parliament?",
    "answerText": 14
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75402,
    "questionText": " Who was the Hindu saint to have as disciple both Hindus and Muslims?",
    "answerText": " Sri Chaitanya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75403,
    "questionText": " During India’s Freedom Struggle; which led to the first ‘All India Hartal’?",
    "answerText": " Protest against Rowlatt Act"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75404,
    "questionText": " Which is the State with the largest area under waste land?",
    "answerText": " Jammu and Kashmir"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75405,
    "questionText": " Pandit K.G. Ginde; was well known for his contribution in when field?",
    "answerText": " Music"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75406,
    "questionText": " Which organism is required for the preparation of alcohol?",
    "answerText": " Fungi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75407,
    "questionText": " What happens; When water is heated from °C to 10°C the volume of water?",
    "answerText": " First decreases then increases"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75408,
    "questionText": " In which year did the first modem Olympic Games take place?",
    "answerText": 1896
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75409,
    "questionText": " What do the Ajanta paintings depict?",
    "answerText": " Scenes from the Jatakas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75410,
    "questionText": " Who was the President of the Indian National Congress at the time of Indian Independence?",
    "answerText": " J. B. Kriplani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75411,
    "questionText": " In which country was Buddhism first propogated outside India?",
    "answerText": " Srilanka"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75412,
    "questionText": " Compared to other slopes in the northern hemisphere which is the warmest?",
    "answerText": " South facing"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75413,
    "questionText": " After how many years One-third of the members of the Rajya Sabha retire?",
    "answerText": " Second year"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75414,
    "questionText": " Which is the producer of copper?",
    "answerText": " Chile"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75415,
    "questionText": " Which polymer is used for making bulletproof material?",
    "answerText": " Polyethylene"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75416,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of the book ‘A bend in the River’?",
    "answerText": " V.S. Naipaul"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75417,
    "questionText": " Which cytoplasmic organelles are treated as prokaryotic cells within the eukaryotic cells?",
    "answerText": " Glyoxysomes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75418,
    "questionText": " Which rivers joins Ganga at Allahabad?",
    "answerText": " Yamuna"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75419,
    "questionText": " Which river crosses the Equator twice?",
    "answerText": " Congo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75420,
    "questionText": " By whom the Mahatma Gandhi was referred to ‘Father of the Nation’ first?",
    "answerText": " Subhash Chandra Bose"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75421,
    "questionText": " Mahamastakabhisheka; a great religious event; is associated with and done for whom?",
    "answerText": " Bahubali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75422,
    "questionText": " The Ruhr-Westphalia region is a famous industrial region of which country?",
    "answerText": " Germany"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75423,
    "questionText": " Amir Khusrau played a pioneer rule in the development of which thing?",
    "answerText": " Khari Boli"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75424,
    "questionText": " Who is known as the ‘Grand Old Man of India’?",
    "answerText": " Dadabhai Naoroji"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75425,
    "questionText": " Vegetative propagation by stem cutting is generally foundation of which plant?",
    "answerText": " Sugarcane"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75426,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of the book “Superstar India From Incredible to Unstopable” ?",
    "answerText": " Sobha De"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75427,
    "questionText": " During whose pleasure does the Attorney General of India hold office?",
    "answerText": " President"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75428,
    "questionText": " What does Nail polish remover contain?",
    "answerText": " Acetone"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75429,
    "questionText": " Which is the most unreactive gas?",
    "answerText": " Hydrogen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75430,
    "questionText": " Where is the headquarters of UNHCR located?",
    "answerText": " Geneva"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75431,
    "questionText": " Which country won the first World Cup cricket tournament in 1975?",
    "answerText": " West Indies"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75432,
    "questionText": " For television broadcasting; what frequency is employed normally?",
    "answerText": " 30 – 300 MHz"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75433,
    "questionText": " Which foreign country is closest to Andarnan Islands?",
    "answerText": " Myanmar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75434,
    "questionText": " Upto where Chandraqupta Maurya's empire extended in the north-west?",
    "answerText": " Hindukush"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75435,
    "questionText": " Jointed appendages are characteristic of which phylum?",
    "answerText": " Arthropoda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75436,
    "questionText": " Who were the ashta-diggaja in the court of Krishnadeva Raya?",
    "answerText": " Eight telugu poets"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75437,
    "questionText": " The Khajuraho shrines built by Chandella rulers are dedicated to which god?",
    "answerText": " Vishnu and Shiva"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75438,
    "questionText": " Who was named as Mira Ben by Mahatma Gandhi?",
    "answerText": " Madeline Slade"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75439,
    "questionText": " Which is the instrument that measures air pressure?",
    "answerText": " Barometer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75440,
    "questionText": " 'Arhai-Din-Ka Jhonpra' built by Qutbuddin Aibak; where is this located?",
    "answerText": " Ajmer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75441,
    "questionText": " What is the number of electrons in an atom of atomic number Z and mass number A?",
    "answerText": " Z"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75442,
    "questionText": " Which new alluvial deposits found in the Gangetic plain?",
    "answerText": " Khadar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75443,
    "questionText": " What is the wavelength of visible spectrum?",
    "answerText": " 3900-7600 A"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75444,
    "questionText": " How many rings on the Olympic flag?",
    "answerText": " Five"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75445,
    "questionText": " Which rock system has the maximum concentration of minerals?",
    "answerText": " Dharwar system"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75446,
    "questionText": " Which authority sanctions foreign exchange for the import of goods?",
    "answerText": " Reserve Bank of India"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75447,
    "questionText": " Indian languages which were added to the official list of 15 in 1992 vide71st amendment of the Constitution are?",
    "answerText": " Konkani; Manipuri and Nepali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75448,
    "questionText": " What is the connecting link between Annelida and Mollusca?",
    "answerText": " Neopalina"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75449,
    "questionText": " Which animal resembles most to human beings in terms of physical and mental capabilities?",
    "answerText": " Chimpanzee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75450,
    "questionText": " Which hormone is responsible for the secretion of milk in mothers?",
    "answerText": " Lactogenic hormone"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75451,
    "questionText": " To which work is Devichandraguptam related?",
    "answerText": " Chandra Gupta II"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75452,
    "questionText": " Which is the largest irrigation canal of the world?",
    "answerText": " Indira Gandhi Canal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75453,
    "questionText": " The Treaty of Amritsar was concluded between Maharaja Ranjit Singh and whom?",
    "answerText": " Lord Minto"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75454,
    "questionText": " Which country is the largest debtor of UNO?",
    "answerText": " U.S."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75455,
    "questionText": " During which Sikh Guru Arjun Dev was killed?",
    "answerText": " Jahangir"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75456,
    "questionText": " Who sings on ten rupee notes?",
    "answerText": " Governor (Reserve Bank of India)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75457,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Indian to become the member of British Parliament?",
    "answerText": " Dadabhai Naoroji"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75458,
    "questionText": " Which endangered Ridley turtles have the world’s largest aggregation?",
    "answerText": " Gahirmatha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75459,
    "questionText": " A metal sheet with circular hole is heated. what change will be in the hole?",
    "answerText": " It will Expand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75460,
    "questionText": " Participatory Notes (PNs) are associated with which investors?",
    "answerText": " Foreign Institutional Investors"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75461,
    "questionText": " What is the best representative of the acid igneous rocks?",
    "answerText": " Granite"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75462,
    "questionText": " Who got the ‘Bharat Ratna’ award; before becoming the President of India?",
    "answerText": " Dr. Zakir Hussain"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75463,
    "questionText": " Bulo C. Rani was associated with which field?",
    "answerText": " Motion picture"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75464,
    "questionText": " Who or what lives in a formicarium?",
    "answerText": " Ants"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75465,
    "questionText": " If the density of water is gcm- in C.G.S. System; what is its value in M.K.S. system?",
    "answerText": " 103 kg m-3"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75466,
    "questionText": " Which type of climate is known for the maximum diurnal range of temperature?",
    "answerText": " Hot desert"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75467,
    "questionText": " Which colloids are solvent loving colloids?",
    "answerText": " Lyophilic"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75468,
    "questionText": " A ‘flower bud’ which is uses as a spice is obtained from which plant?",
    "answerText": " Clove"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75469,
    "questionText": " The first Indian to cross seven important seas by swimming?",
    "answerText": " Bula Chaudhary"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75470,
    "questionText": " When can one record the lowest temperature of air?",
    "answerText": " Just before sunrise"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75471,
    "questionText": " From the biological evolutionary point of view; the human heart is close to the heart of which animal?",
    "answerText": " Pig"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75472,
    "questionText": " In which year Swarn Jayanti Gram Swa-Rozgar Yojna came into being?",
    "answerText": " 1-Apr-1999"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75473,
    "questionText": " Where is Greeco-Roman influence in Indian art found?",
    "answerText": " Gandhara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75474,
    "questionText": " Which organelle is present in bacteria or prokaryotic cell?",
    "answerText": " Ribosomes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75475,
    "questionText": " Of which thing were the Indus Valley houses built?",
    "answerText": " Bricks"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75476,
    "questionText": " When is United Nations Day for Women Rights and International Peace observed?",
    "answerText": " 8-Mar-2017"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75477,
    "questionText": " Which planet is known as the Earth’s Twin?",
    "answerText": " Venus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75478,
    "questionText": " Which Indian state is known as ‘Land of Five Rivers’?",
    "answerText": " Punjab"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75479,
    "questionText": " Daily weather map showing isobars is an example of which map?",
    "answerText": " Chropleth map"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75480,
    "questionText": " By whom was Nishat Garden built?",
    "answerText": " Jahangir"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75481,
    "questionText": " Which describes India as a Secular State?",
    "answerText": " Preamble to the Constitution"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75482,
    "questionText": " Who built the tomb of her Emperor husband?",
    "answerText": " Haji Beghum"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75483,
    "questionText": " Taxation and the government’s expenditure policy are dealt under which policy?",
    "answerText": " Fiscal policy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75484,
    "questionText": " Who is the leading wicket taker in the history of Test Cricket?",
    "answerText": " Muttiah Muralitharan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75485,
    "questionText": " What is a line on a weather map joining all places of equal pressure called?",
    "answerText": " Isobar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75486,
    "questionText": " ‘Alice in Wonderland’ the famous TV Serial; is based on a book written by which author?",
    "answerText": " Lewis Caroll"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75487,
    "questionText": " Which product is the export leading from India in the terms of value?",
    "answerText": " Gems and Jwellery"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75488,
    "questionText": " What is the negative logarithmic value of hydrogen on called?",
    "answerText": " pH"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75489,
    "questionText": " Which unicellular non-pathogenic parasite is found in the human intestine?",
    "answerText": " E; coli"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75490,
    "questionText": " Which chemical used as a ‘fixer’ in photography?",
    "answerText": " Sodium thiosulphate"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75491,
    "questionText": " Which contenent has the lowest growth rate of population?",
    "answerText": " Europe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75492,
    "questionText": " Through which are water and mineral in plant are transported?",
    "answerText": " Xylem"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75493,
    "questionText": " During which Five Year Plan was the total expenditure on agriculture the highest?",
    "answerText": " Fourth Five Year Plan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75494,
    "questionText": " What was the mascot for the 2012 Olympic Games held in London?",
    "answerText": " Wenlock"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75495,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of the book “The Audacity of Hope”?",
    "answerText": " Barack Obama"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75496,
    "questionText": " The direction of ocean currents is reversed with season in which ocean?",
    "answerText": " In the Indian Ocean"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75497,
    "questionText": " Which first feature film (talkie) produced in India?",
    "answerText": " Alamm Ara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75498,
    "questionText": " To whom is a minister in a State individually responsible?",
    "answerText": " Governor"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75499,
    "questionText": " The world famous ‘Khajuraho’ sculptures are located in which State?",
    "answerText": " Madhya Pradesh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75500,
    "questionText": " Which is the most important ore of aluminium?",
    "answerText": " Bauxite"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75501,
    "questionText": " Which oil field of India is the oldest and still producing oil?",
    "answerText": " Digboi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75502,
    "questionText": " Tansen Samman has been instituted by the Government of which state?",
    "answerText": " Madhya Pradesh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75503,
    "questionText": " Funds belonging to the Government of India are kept in which fund?",
    "answerText": " Consolidated Fund of India"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75504,
    "questionText": " What is good source of protein?",
    "answerText": " Soyabean"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75505,
    "questionText": " Limba Ram is associated with which field?",
    "answerText": " Sports"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75506,
    "questionText": " Who is the first Indian woman to receive in Borlaug award and in which year?",
    "answerText": " Dr. Amita Patel; 1992"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75507,
    "questionText": " The pH of water at 25°C is When it is heated to 100°C; then what will be the pH of water?",
    "answerText": " Remains same"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75508,
    "questionText": " Which can one come across if one travels through the Strait of Malacca?",
    "answerText": " Singapore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75509,
    "questionText": " During the reign of Iltutmish which was a silver coin in use?",
    "answerText": " Tanka"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75510,
    "questionText": " Who attended the Second Round Table Conference as the representative of the Congress?",
    "answerText": " Gandhiji"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75511,
    "questionText": " What is in lichen symbiotic relationship between fungi and algae called?",
    "answerText": " Halotism"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75512,
    "questionText": " The famous player Pele is associated with which game?",
    "answerText": " Football"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75513,
    "questionText": " Which is a land-locked sea?",
    "answerText": " Aral Sea"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75514,
    "questionText": " Who had the Revenue system during Akbar’s reign?",
    "answerText": " Todar Mal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75515,
    "questionText": " In which hemisphere does India lie?",
    "answerText": " Northern and eastern"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75516,
    "questionText": " Which country won the Cricket World Cup in 2011?",
    "answerText": " India"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75517,
    "questionText": " Where was the first oil well in India was dug?",
    "answerText": " Digboi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75518,
    "questionText": " Where was the All India Muslim League formed in 1906?",
    "answerText": " Dacca"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75519,
    "questionText": " Which compound can not be used as nitrogenous fertilizer?",
    "answerText": " HNO3"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75520,
    "questionText": " India is the seventh largest country in the world and how much does it cover a total area?",
    "answerText": " Approximately 3200000 sq. km"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75521,
    "questionText": " Which chemical is most suitable to control storage insects on a small scale?",
    "answerText": " B. H. C."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75522,
    "questionText": " In which forest the maximum plant diversity is found?",
    "answerText": " Tropical evergreen forests"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75523,
    "questionText": " Which day is celebrated as the International Labour Day?",
    "answerText": " 1-May-2017"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75524,
    "questionText": " Which is a cash crop?",
    "answerText": " Rubber"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75525,
    "questionText": " In 1889 a British Committee of the Indian National Congress was started. Who was its Chairman?",
    "answerText": " W. Wedderburn"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75526,
    "questionText": " Who was associated with supression of Thugs?",
    "answerText": " Captain Sleeman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75527,
    "questionText": " When was World Council of Churches formally constituted?",
    "answerText": " 23rd August; 1948"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75528,
    "questionText": " In which veda is the ancient time state craft and polity described?",
    "answerText": " Arthashastra"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75529,
    "questionText": " When did Ikhtiyaruddin-bin-Bakhtiyar Khalji invade Bengal?",
    "answerText": " 1206 AD"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75530,
    "questionText": " Sound become hazardous noise pollution at which level?",
    "answerText": " Above 80 dB"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75531,
    "questionText": " Which ruler established embassies in foreign countries on modern lines?",
    "answerText": " Tipu Sultan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75532,
    "questionText": " The Rajatarangini by Kalhana 'is Sanskrit verse; when was it written?",
    "answerText": " 12th century A.D."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75533,
    "questionText": " How must be the The lines of force of a uniform magnetic field?",
    "answerText": " Parallel to each other"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75534,
    "questionText": " To which battle of the beginning of the British political sway over India can be traced?",
    "answerText": " Plassey"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75535,
    "questionText": " Who is well known for his contribution in the field of Algebra?",
    "answerText": " Bhaskara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75536,
    "questionText": " Which latitude passes through India?",
    "answerText": " Tropic of Cancer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75537,
    "questionText": " Megasthenese was the Ambassador of which ruler?",
    "answerText": " Seleucus Nikator"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75538,
    "questionText": " How is Manimekalai is looked?",
    "answerText": " As the Odyssey of Tamil"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75539,
    "questionText": " Anglo-Indian representatives in the Lok Sabha are nominated in terms of which Article?",
    "answerText": 331
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75540,
    "questionText": " Who is the world’s first woman cosmonaut?",
    "answerText": " Valentina Tereshkova"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75541,
    "questionText": " Who is the first Air Chief to receive the honour of “Marshal”?",
    "answerText": " Arjun Singh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75542,
    "questionText": " Which Act formally introduced the principles of elections for the first time?",
    "answerText": " Indian Councils Act; 1909"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75543,
    "questionText": " What is treatment of body defects through massage and exercise?",
    "answerText": " Physiotherapy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75544,
    "questionText": " Which coastline formed by the submergence of mountain ridges running parallel to the coast?",
    "answerText": " Dalmation coast"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75545,
    "questionText": " One day in Mumbai a tide occurs at 00 A.M. when will it occur the next day?",
    "answerText": " 8 : 26 A.M."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75546,
    "questionText": " Which gas is most predominant in the Sun?",
    "answerText": " Hydrogen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75547,
    "questionText": " During which movement was ‘Mahatma’ added before Gandhiji’s name?",
    "answerText": " Champaran satyagraha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75548,
    "questionText": " Who is regarded as the founder of the scientific Socialism?",
    "answerText": " Karl Marx"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75549,
    "questionText": " Where is the intensity of the earth’s gravitational field maximum?",
    "answerText": " At the pole"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75550,
    "questionText": " Which is the country with the highest density?",
    "answerText": " Singapore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75551,
    "questionText": " Which Sikh Gurus started the Gurumukhi script?",
    "answerText": " Guru Angad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75552,
    "questionText": " Which radiation emitted from the sun has highest wavelength?",
    "answerText": " Micro waves"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75553,
    "questionText": " What is associated with a savanna climate?",
    "answerText": " Scrub"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75554,
    "questionText": " When was West African Monetary and Economic Union found?",
    "answerText": 1994
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75555,
    "questionText": " Among the Indian languages; which one is spoken maximum in the world after Hindi?",
    "answerText": " Bengali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75556,
    "questionText": " Which place gets the least rainfall?",
    "answerText": " Jodhpur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75557,
    "questionText": " When is World Hospice and Palliative Care Day observed?",
    "answerText": 44843
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75558,
    "questionText": " On which Panchayat did the Ashok Mehta Committee greater emphasis?",
    "answerText": " Mandai Panchayat"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75559,
    "questionText": " Apart from Tamil Nadu; lignite is found in which state?",
    "answerText": " Gujarat"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75560,
    "questionText": " Who was made the Home Minister when Jawaharlal Nehru formed the Interim Government in 1946?",
    "answerText": " Sardar Patel"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75561,
    "questionText": " The World Water Conservation Day is observed on which date?",
    "answerText": " 22-Mar-2017"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75562,
    "questionText": " How many image will be formed if two mirrors are fitted adjacent walls and one mirror on ceiling?",
    "answerText": 7
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75563,
    "questionText": " What is the respect for the National Flag and National Anthem?",
    "answerText": " Fundamental Duty of every citizen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75564,
    "questionText": " What are “Open Market Operations”?",
    "answerText": " Selling of giltedged securities by the Government"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75565,
    "questionText": " Who produced the first film in India ‘Raja Harishchandra’ in 1913?",
    "answerText": " Dada Saheb Phalke"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75566,
    "questionText": " The equatorial regions receive rainfall throughout the year. What is the annual rainfall?",
    "answerText": " 250 cms"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75567,
    "questionText": " Under which system of assessment; the British Government collected revenue directly from the farmers?",
    "answerText": " Ryotwari"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75568,
    "questionText": " Which country is known as the ‘Sugar bowl of the World’?",
    "answerText": " Cuba"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75569,
    "questionText": " In equatorial regions How is the temperature between July and January?",
    "answerText": " The same"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75570,
    "questionText": " By whom are the oldest compositions in Punjabi devotional compositions?",
    "answerText": " Baba Farid"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75571,
    "questionText": " Which was India’s first-ever tactical missile?",
    "answerText": " Agni"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75572,
    "questionText": " By whom were India’s famous Peacock Throne and the diamond Koh-e-Noor taken away?",
    "answerText": " Nadir Shah"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75573,
    "questionText": " Which is the largest fresh water lake in the world?",
    "answerText": " Lake Superior"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75574,
    "questionText": " In which technology do Cryogenic engines find applications?",
    "answerText": " Rocket technology"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75575,
    "questionText": " Which metal has the highest density?",
    "answerText": " Platinum"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75576,
    "questionText": " Which was the 1st non Test playing country to befit India in an international match?",
    "answerText": " Sri Lanka"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75577,
    "questionText": " In which region of India was the Suharawadi order of Sufism popular?",
    "answerText": " Punjab and Sind"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75578,
    "questionText": " National Flower of India?",
    "answerText": " LOTUS"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75579,
    "questionText": " What is the outermost layer of Sun called?",
    "answerText": " Corona"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75580,
    "questionText": " Which is the fastest growing tree?",
    "answerText": " Eucalyptus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75581,
    "questionText": " Comets revolve around which body?",
    "answerText": " Sun"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75582,
    "questionText": " Which decade is celebrated as Bone and Joint Decade; recognised by WHO?",
    "answerText": " 2001-2010"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75583,
    "questionText": " From where did Mahatma Gandhi start his historic Dandi March?",
    "answerText": " Sabarmati Ashram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75584,
    "questionText": " Which Insectivorous fish used for mosquito control?",
    "answerText": " Gambusia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75585,
    "questionText": " Which city was regarded as the best producer of silk?",
    "answerText": " Varanasi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75586,
    "questionText": " Which is the largest Public Sector Bank in India?",
    "answerText": " State Bank of India"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75587,
    "questionText": " Thyroid gland is activated by which harmonic for the secretion of thyroxin?",
    "answerText": " TSH"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75588,
    "questionText": " Indra Nooyi is the Chief Executive Officer of which company?",
    "answerText": " Pepsi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75589,
    "questionText": " Where is respiratory centre situated?",
    "answerText": " Medulla oblongata"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75590,
    "questionText": " Which is called philosopher’s wool?",
    "answerText": " Zinc oxide"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75591,
    "questionText": " What is not the cause of low conductivity of electrolyte?",
    "answerText": " Ionisation of salt"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75592,
    "questionText": " Why do The clouds float in the atmosphere?",
    "answerText": " Because of their low temperature"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75593,
    "questionText": " If the earth were to skin faster; how does acceleration due to gravity at the poles?",
    "answerText": " Remains the same"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75594,
    "questionText": " PINCODE was started in the year?",
    "answerText": 1972
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75595,
    "questionText": " How is the contribution of agriculture to India’s economy?",
    "answerText": " Decreasing"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75596,
    "questionText": " Which is the main river flowing in the state of Jammu and Kashmir?",
    "answerText": " Jhelum"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75597,
    "questionText": " In which language did Buddha preach?",
    "answerText": " Pali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75598,
    "questionText": " Which groups suffer the most from inflation?",
    "answerText": " Creditors"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75599,
    "questionText": " Which organ breaks fat to produce cholesterol?",
    "answerText": " Liver"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75600,
    "questionText": " Amar Singh Sokhi is remembered for his performance in which sports event?",
    "answerText": " Cycling"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75601,
    "questionText": " In which year did India first take part in the Olympic Games?",
    "answerText": 1920
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75602,
    "questionText": " Which organ destroys worn out RBCs in the body of a vertebrate?",
    "answerText": " Spleen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75603,
    "questionText": " Which psychologist invented the terms introvert and extrovert?",
    "answerText": " Carl Jung"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75604,
    "questionText": " Who is believed to have created the raga Miyan Ki Malhar?",
    "answerText": " Tansen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75605,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Test centurion in Indian Cricket?",
    "answerText": " Lala Amarnath"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75606,
    "questionText": " On planet Earth; where is no centrifugal force?",
    "answerText": " At the Poles"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75607,
    "questionText": " When viewed in white light; why do soap bubbles show colours?",
    "answerText": " Because of interference"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75608,
    "questionText": " A Buddhist Council during the reign of Kanishka was held at which place?",
    "answerText": " Kashmir"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75609,
    "questionText": " Which woman has become the highest individual scorer in an innings in Tests?",
    "answerText": " Kiran Baloch"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75610,
    "questionText": " Who has been designated as the chairman by the IBA?",
    "answerText": " K. R. Kamath"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75611,
    "questionText": " Which factor does not have influence on the Indian climate?",
    "answerText": " Ocean currents"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75612,
    "questionText": " Which is the longest national Highway in India?",
    "answerText": " NH 7"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75613,
    "questionText": " What is a line on a map which joins places having the same rainfall called?",
    "answerText": " Isohyet"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75614,
    "questionText": " In the Sultanate period; which was the highest rural authority for land revenue?",
    "answerText": " Chowdhary"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75615,
    "questionText": " What is the name of the person that controls a football match?",
    "answerText": " An umpire"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75616,
    "questionText": " A far-sighted person has a near point at 100 cm. What must be the power of the correcting lens?",
    "answerText": " +3.0 D"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75617,
    "questionText": " Who said; “Good government was never a good substitute for self government”?",
    "answerText": " Swami Dayananda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75618,
    "questionText": " Which is not a form of precipitation?",
    "answerText": " Fog"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75619,
    "questionText": " Which ruler died while playing 'Chaugan'?",
    "answerText": " Jalal-ud-din-Khilji"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75620,
    "questionText": " In what commodity the English first conducted trade from India?",
    "answerText": " Indigo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75621,
    "questionText": " Which petroleum refinery product has the lowest boiling point?",
    "answerText": " Gasoline"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75622,
    "questionText": " Where are the disputes regarding the election of the President and Vice-President settle?",
    "answerText": " In the Supreme Court"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75623,
    "questionText": " Which is the most important small-scale industry in India?",
    "answerText": " Handloom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75624,
    "questionText": " Where is the headquarters of African Export and Import Bank?",
    "answerText": " Egypt"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75625,
    "questionText": " Who said “My boy no; you are an Indian first and then a Muslim”?",
    "answerText": " Mohammad Ali Jinnah"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75626,
    "questionText": " Trade Union comes under which List?",
    "answerText": " Concurrent list"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75627,
    "questionText": " Who had called Subhash Chandra Bose as ‘Desh Nayak’?",
    "answerText": " Rabindranath Tagore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75628,
    "questionText": " Which plant is used for green manuring in India?",
    "answerText": " Sunhemp"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75629,
    "questionText": " Who invented the laser?",
    "answerText": " Charles H. Townes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75630,
    "questionText": " Hitendra Desai was a noted figure in which field?",
    "answerText": " Politics"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75631,
    "questionText": " The equator cuts through which islands?",
    "answerText": " Borneo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75632,
    "questionText": " With Which game is the Double Fault associated?",
    "answerText": " Football"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75633,
    "questionText": " Gangotri; Yamunotri; Kedarnath; Badrinath and Mussorie lies in which state?",
    "answerText": " Uttrakhand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75634,
    "questionText": " Who has been awarded the Prem Bhatia Award for the year 2012?",
    "answerText": " P.R. Ramesh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75635,
    "questionText": " Which is the main difference between the Western and Eastern Ghats?",
    "answerText": " Continuity"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75636,
    "questionText": " The United Nations declared 2012 as the International Year of which thing?",
    "answerText": " Cooperatives"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75637,
    "questionText": " Local thunderstorms ‘Norwesters’ are prominent in which state?",
    "answerText": " West Bengal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75638,
    "questionText": " During electrolysis; which the species are discharged at cathode?",
    "answerText": " Cations"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75639,
    "questionText": " Which is the largest irrigation canal in the world?",
    "answerText": " Indira Gandhi Canal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75640,
    "questionText": " Angel falls Venezuela Highest whaterfalls but where second Highest?",
    "answerText": " Yosemite USA"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75641,
    "questionText": " A person to be qualified for standing in a panchayat election what age must have he attained?",
    "answerText": " 21 years"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75642,
    "questionText": " India is self sufficient in production of which of the following commodities?",
    "answerText": " Milk"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75643,
    "questionText": " In a living cell what is the site of ribosome formation?",
    "answerText": " Nucleolus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75644,
    "questionText": " Late Ustad Nisar Hussain Khan earned distinction in which fields?",
    "answerText": " Vocal music"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75645,
    "questionText": " On which river did Pulakesin II defeat Harshavardhana?",
    "answerText": " Narmada"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75646,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Indian to get selected in ICS?",
    "answerText": " Surendranath Banerjee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75647,
    "questionText": " How is the speed of light with the rise in the temperature of the medium?",
    "answerText": " Remains unaltered"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75648,
    "questionText": " If the temperature of a patient is 40°C; what will be his temperature on Fahrenheit scale?",
    "answerText": " 104° F"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75649,
    "questionText": " What is an essential attribute of inflation?",
    "answerText": " Increase in prices"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75650,
    "questionText": " Who established Diwan-i-Mustakharaj (Department of Arrears)?",
    "answerText": " Alauddin Khalji"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75651,
    "questionText": " Which is the longest inland waterways in the world?",
    "answerText": " Mississippi river system"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75652,
    "questionText": " On which do Companies pay Corporation Tax?",
    "answerText": " Incomes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75653,
    "questionText": " How do fogs formed along the sea-coast?",
    "answerText": " Due to advection"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75654,
    "questionText": " Which compound is used for writing on glass?",
    "answerText": " Hydrogen fluoride"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75655,
    "questionText": " Who wrote the book “A nation in the making”?",
    "answerText": " Surendranath Banerjee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75656,
    "questionText": " Which game is Davis Cup associated with?",
    "answerText": " Tennis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75657,
    "questionText": " Which is the home of “Alphonso” mango?",
    "answerText": " Ratnagiri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75658,
    "questionText": " Who has written the famous book ‘Anna Karenina’?",
    "answerText": " Leo Tolstoy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75659,
    "questionText": " By virtue of which Act; dyarchy was introduced in India?",
    "answerText": " Government of India Act; 1919"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75660,
    "questionText": " The Naga hills form the watershed between India and which country?",
    "answerText": " Myanmar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75661,
    "questionText": " The internal secretion of which acid helps in digestion?",
    "answerText": " Hydrochloric acid"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75662,
    "questionText": " According to the law of demand; what happens when price increases?",
    "answerText": " Demand decreases"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75663,
    "questionText": " What is known as venus’s flower?",
    "answerText": " Euplectella"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75664,
    "questionText": " Wood pulp comes from which region?",
    "answerText": " Coniferous forest region"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75665,
    "questionText": " Who has won Man of the Match award in the 2011 World Cup Cricket?",
    "answerText": " MS Dohni"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75666,
    "questionText": " What is the characteristic odour of garlic?",
    "answerText": " A sulphur compound"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75667,
    "questionText": " The change in temperature of a body is 50°C. What is the change on Kelvin scale?",
    "answerText": " 50 K"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75668,
    "questionText": " In India; maximum number of newspapers are published which language?",
    "answerText": " Hindi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75669,
    "questionText": " Which school of paintings developed independently during the Mughal Period?",
    "answerText": " The Bijapur School"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75670,
    "questionText": " Who was the founder of Sunga dynasty?",
    "answerText": " Pushyamitra"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75671,
    "questionText": " The Fundamental Right to Property has been deleted by the which Amendment Act?",
    "answerText": " 44th"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75672,
    "questionText": " The western disturbances which cause rain in north west India originate which sea?",
    "answerText": " Mediterranean Sea"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75673,
    "questionText": " What is a person of mixed European and Indian blood in Latin America is called?",
    "answerText": " Mestizo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75674,
    "questionText": " In which inscription was the name Dharmasoka found?",
    "answerText": " Sarnath Inscription"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75675,
    "questionText": " Which is the essential element in all organic compounds?",
    "answerText": " Carbon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75676,
    "questionText": " Who was the Sikh Guru to be slaughtered by Aurangzeb?",
    "answerText": " Teg Bahadur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75677,
    "questionText": " Which countries translated name means Land of the Eagle?",
    "answerText": " Albania"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75678,
    "questionText": " Which part of separated UTI is under SEBI’s regulation?",
    "answerText": " UTI-II"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75679,
    "questionText": " Who sent Hienu-Tsang as an envoy to Harsha’s’ court?",
    "answerText": " Tai Tsung"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75680,
    "questionText": " By whom was oral polio vaccine discovered?",
    "answerText": " Jonas Salk"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75681,
    "questionText": " Under which reign did Mughal Empire extend up to Tamil territory in the South?",
    "answerText": " Aurangzeb"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75682,
    "questionText": " For whom was the Peacock throne made?",
    "answerText": " Shahjahan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75683,
    "questionText": " Which sea on Earth has no beaches?",
    "answerText": " Sargasso sea"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75684,
    "questionText": " Alzheimer’s disease in human beings is characterised by which degeneration?",
    "answerText": " Degeneration of nerve cells"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75685,
    "questionText": " With Which game/sport is ‘Popping crease’ associated?",
    "answerText": " Cricket"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75686,
    "questionText": " Who was a blind poet who worshipped Krishna and spread Krishna Bhakti cult?",
    "answerText": " Surdas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75687,
    "questionText": " What is the radius of the earth approximately?",
    "answerText": " 6400 km"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75688,
    "questionText": " Chand Bibi; who ceded Berar to Akbar; was the ruler of which kingdom?",
    "answerText": " Ahmednagar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75689,
    "questionText": " Which Rajputa king defeated Muhammad Ghori for the first time?",
    "answerText": " Prithviraj III"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75690,
    "questionText": " In human body; into which does the pancreas secretes its enzymes?",
    "answerText": " Duodenum"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75691,
    "questionText": " Who among the following was the first Indian to receive the Magsaysay award?",
    "answerText": " Vinoba Bhave"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75692,
    "questionText": " A place having an average annual temperature of 27°C and an annual rainfall of over 200 cm.where is this?",
    "answerText": " Singapore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75693,
    "questionText": " When is International Human Solidarity Day observed?",
    "answerText": " 20-Dec-2017"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75694,
    "questionText": " Of which kingdom was Malik Ambar the Prime Minister?",
    "answerText": " Ahrnadnagar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75695,
    "questionText": " By whom is the Chairman of the Public Accounts Committee of the Parliament appointed?",
    "answerText": " Speaker of Lok Sabha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75696,
    "questionText": " Which High Court has jurisdiction over the State of Arunachal Pradesh?",
    "answerText": " Mumbai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75697,
    "questionText": " What is the escape velocity of a particle of mass m varies?",
    "answerText": " mo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75698,
    "questionText": " How is Swami Vivekananda’s birthday observed in India?",
    "answerText": " As National Youth Day"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75699,
    "questionText": " Which mirror is to be used to obtain a parallel beam of light from a small lamp?",
    "answerText": " Concave mirror"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75700,
    "questionText": " The river Cauvery flows from which state?",
    "answerText": " Karnataka to Tamil Nadu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75701,
    "questionText": " What is the unit of luminous efficiency of an electric bulb?",
    "answerText": " Lumen / watt"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75702,
    "questionText": " The United Nations declared as which International Year?",
    "answerText": " Reconciliation"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75703,
    "questionText": " When is World Day Against Death Penalty; recognized by the WCADP observed?",
    "answerText": " 10-Oct-2017"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75704,
    "questionText": " What is the largest lymphatic organ of the body?",
    "answerText": " Spleen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75705,
    "questionText": " Mughal dynasty was to Bahadur Shah Zafar-as what was Lodi dynasty to?",
    "answerText": " Ibrahim Lodi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75706,
    "questionText": " How many image can a man see if he stands between two plane mirrors inclined at an angle of 60°?",
    "answerText": 5
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75707,
    "questionText": " Sushil Kumar is associated with which Game?",
    "answerText": " Wrestling"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75708,
    "questionText": " In which list are the Central Government’s exclusive powers enumerated?",
    "answerText": " Union List"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75709,
    "questionText": " The release of which fish into ponds and wells helps in controlling the mosquitoes?",
    "answerText": " Gambusia fish"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75710,
    "questionText": " What is Hepatitis-B; which affects liver?",
    "answerText": " Virus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75711,
    "questionText": " Where is the headquarter of International atomic Energy Agency is located?",
    "answerText": " Vienna"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75712,
    "questionText": " ‘I have nothing to offer except blood; sweat and tears’ was said by which person?",
    "answerText": " Churchill"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75713,
    "questionText": " Which is a typical feature of volcanic eruption?",
    "answerText": " Dykes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75714,
    "questionText": " By whom was Din-i-Ilahi was accepted?",
    "answerText": " Birbal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75715,
    "questionText": " Which music composers was deaf?",
    "answerText": " Beethovan L.V."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75716,
    "questionText": " Which of the planets is nearest to the earth?",
    "answerText": " Venus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75717,
    "questionText": " A vein is a vessel that carries blood which side?",
    "answerText": " Towards the heart"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75718,
    "questionText": " The emission of which greenhouse gase of which entirely anthropogenic?",
    "answerText": " Chlorofluorocarbons"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75719,
    "questionText": " Which non-metals is not a poor conductor of electricity?",
    "answerText": " Selenium"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75720,
    "questionText": " Einstein’s mass energy relation is given by which expression?",
    "answerText": " E = mc2"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75721,
    "questionText": " In which festival are boat races a special feature?",
    "answerText": " Onam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75722,
    "questionText": " The Konkan Coast stretches between which regions?",
    "answerText": " Goa and Cochin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75723,
    "questionText": " The Lok Sabha is called in session for at least how many times in a year’?",
    "answerText": " Thrice"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75724,
    "questionText": " Lathyrism is caused by excessive consumption of which thing?",
    "answerText": " Khesari Dal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75725,
    "questionText": " Which are the metal that is present in photo films?",
    "answerText": " Silver"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75726,
    "questionText": " If an ideal gas is isothermally expanded; what will its internal energy?",
    "answerText": " Remain the same"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75727,
    "questionText": " Why is used as coolant in the radiator of a car engine?",
    "answerText": " Because it has high specific heat"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75728,
    "questionText": " Who has been named as the White Lightning in the cricket?",
    "answerText": " Allan Donald (South Africa)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75729,
    "questionText": " Pollination takes place with the help of bird; what is called?",
    "answerText": " Ornithophily"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75730,
    "questionText": " Which was the main characteristic of the later Vedic age?",
    "answerText": " Caste system"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75731,
    "questionText": " Where had Buddha delivered maximum sermons?",
    "answerText": " Sravasti"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75732,
    "questionText": " Which of the following has been found useful in keeping cholesterol level down?",
    "answerText": " Garlic"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75733,
    "questionText": " In which is the largest population of Scheduled Tribes?",
    "answerText": " Madhya Pradesh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75734,
    "questionText": " Which river has the largest drainage basin?",
    "answerText": " Amazon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75735,
    "questionText": " After how many years is the President of USA is elected?",
    "answerText": " 4 years"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75736,
    "questionText": " Which is a source of methane emission into the atmosphere?",
    "answerText": " Wetland"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75737,
    "questionText": " What are the Mediterranean lands often called?",
    "answerText": " World’s orchard lands"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75738,
    "questionText": " Which element that does not occur in nature but can be produced artificially?",
    "answerText": " Plutonium"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75739,
    "questionText": " Who founded the Banaras Hindu University?",
    "answerText": " Madan Mohan Malviya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75740,
    "questionText": " Which substance does not have a melting point?",
    "answerText": " Glass"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75741,
    "questionText": " What is not a digestive enzyme in human system?",
    "answerText": " Gastrin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75742,
    "questionText": " For international payments; to which currency is the Indian currency linked?",
    "answerText": " American Dollar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75743,
    "questionText": " Which vitamin is considered to be a hormone?",
    "answerText": " D"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75744,
    "questionText": " Which Act removed the legal recognition of slavery in India?",
    "answerText": " The Act V of 1843"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75745,
    "questionText": " Fish die in water bodies polluted by sewage; why?",
    "answerText": " Due to Reduction in oxygen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75746,
    "questionText": " Which is considered an encyclopedia of Indian Medicine?",
    "answerText": " Charaka Samhita"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75747,
    "questionText": " Which country has the largest known reserves of oil?",
    "answerText": " Kuwait"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75748,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Mughal emperor to allow Britishers to establish trade links with India?",
    "answerText": " Jahangir"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75749,
    "questionText": " Which is the largest island in the Indian Ocean?",
    "answerText": " Madagascar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75750,
    "questionText": " With reference to the Revolt of 1857; who laid siege to Jhansi in March 1858?",
    "answerText": " Sir Hugh Rose1"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75751,
    "questionText": " Which kingdom was annexed by Bahlol Lodi; the Sultan of Delhi; in A.D. 1484?",
    "answerText": " Jaunpur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75752,
    "questionText": " Which is used extensively for genetic engineering in plant?",
    "answerText": " Agrobacterium tumefaciens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75753,
    "questionText": " Foot-and-Mouth disease in animals; a current epidemic in some parts of the world; By which is this caused?",
    "answerText": " Bacterium"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75754,
    "questionText": " Which is used as a material for making protective windows in space probes?",
    "answerText": " Diamond"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75755,
    "questionText": " Which river flows through a rift valley?",
    "answerText": " Narmada"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75756,
    "questionText": " Which part of brain is centre of thirst hunger and sleep?",
    "answerText": " Hypothalmus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75757,
    "questionText": " Which is the substance which can act both as an acid and a base?",
    "answerText": " Amphoteric"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75758,
    "questionText": " How can fertility of soil be improved?",
    "answerText": " By adding living earthworms"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75759,
    "questionText": " Who started the Bhoodan Movement?",
    "answerText": " Acharya Vinoba Bhave"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75760,
    "questionText": " The treaty of Bassein (1802) was signed with the British by which Peshwa?",
    "answerText": " Baji Rao II"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75761,
    "questionText": " The Himalyas are approximately how many kilometer long?",
    "answerText": 2500
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75762,
    "questionText": " Which metal is not attacked by the environment?",
    "answerText": " Gold"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75763,
    "questionText": " The Appalachian coal fields; one of the important coal fields in the world; are located in which country?",
    "answerText": " U.S.A."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75764,
    "questionText": " What is the number of plant species estimated to be present in India?",
    "answerText": 40000
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75765,
    "questionText": " Which state ranks first in terms of the maximum number of agro-based industries?",
    "answerText": " Punjab"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75766,
    "questionText": " Which is a part of the eye that helps in changing the focal length of crystalline lensis?",
    "answerText": " Ciliary muscles"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75767,
    "questionText": " On which river is located Indo- Pak Bagalihar Project?",
    "answerText": " Chenab"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75768,
    "questionText": " How many members are there in the International Finance Corporation?",
    "answerText": 184
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75769,
    "questionText": " Maharashtrian Plateau is made up of which?",
    "answerText": " Lava"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75770,
    "questionText": " Which plant produces seeds but not flowers?",
    "answerText": " Groundnut"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75771,
    "questionText": " The book ‘Satanic Verses’ was written by which author?",
    "answerText": " Salman Rushdie"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75772,
    "questionText": " What will be best colours for a Sun umbrella?",
    "answerText": " White on top and black on inside"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75773,
    "questionText": " Which fungy causes green ear disease of bajra?",
    "answerText": " Sclerospora graminicola"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75774,
    "questionText": " In which movements Bande Mataram was adopted as a slogan for agitation?",
    "answerText": " Partition of Bengal in 1905"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75775,
    "questionText": " In where were Bengal the headquarters of East India Company located?",
    "answerText": " Fort William"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75776,
    "questionText": " Which Rashtrakuta ruler established a victory pillar in Rameshwaram?",
    "answerText": " Krishna III"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75777,
    "questionText": " Which Part of plant is important for the life cycle of plant?",
    "answerText": " Flower"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75778,
    "questionText": " What is the average salinity of sea water?",
    "answerText": 0.035
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75779,
    "questionText": " The Dogger Bank; the main fishing area of Europe; where is this area?",
    "answerText": " North Sea"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75780,
    "questionText": " Tulsidas composed his ‘Ramcharitamanasa’ in the reign of which ruler?",
    "answerText": " Akbar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75781,
    "questionText": " Which last atmospheric layer has an altitude greater than 80 kilometers?",
    "answerText": " Thermosphere"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75782,
    "questionText": " By whom are the planets are kept in motion in their respective orbits?",
    "answerText": " Gravitation and centrifugal force"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75783,
    "questionText": " Besides water and light which is more essential as a raw material for photosynthesis?",
    "answerText": " CO2"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75784,
    "questionText": " Which was the most prominent industry that f1uorished during the Mughal period?",
    "answerText": " Cotton textiles"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75785,
    "questionText": " Who founded four mathas in the four comers of India?",
    "answerText": " Shankaracharya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75786,
    "questionText": " Which is used in welding industry?",
    "answerText": " Acetylene"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75787,
    "questionText": " Which city is at the highest altitude above mean sea level?",
    "answerText": " Bangalore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75788,
    "questionText": " The Mughal ruler Bahadur Shah II was exiled by British and where was to sent?",
    "answerText": " Mandalay"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75789,
    "questionText": " Which Tomar ruler is credited to have established Delhi?",
    "answerText": " Anangpal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75790,
    "questionText": " Spice saffron is obtained from which part of plant?",
    "answerText": " Stigma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75791,
    "questionText": " United nations adopted a charter of Economic Rights in which year?",
    "answerText": 1974
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75792,
    "questionText": " Animal goes under winter sleep due to low temperature; what is called?",
    "answerText": " Aestivation"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75793,
    "questionText": " Of whom was Tulsidas was a contemporary?",
    "answerText": " Akbar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75794,
    "questionText": " Which was the Prince who was responsible for the death of his father?",
    "answerText": " Ajatasatru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75795,
    "questionText": " A liquid will not wet the surface of solid if the angle of contact is which angle?",
    "answerText": " Obtuse"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75796,
    "questionText": " What is the introduction of foreign genes for improving genotype?",
    "answerText": " Immunisation"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75797,
    "questionText": " What is pH of human blood?",
    "answerText": " From 7.5 to 8"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75798,
    "questionText": " Who built the temple of the Sun God at Konark?",
    "answerText": " Kapilendra"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75799,
    "questionText": " Which country is not a member of SAARC?",
    "answerText": " Mauritius"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75800,
    "questionText": " The Grand Banks are famous fishing grounds in which region?",
    "answerText": " North-West Atlantic"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75801,
    "questionText": " In which year was ‘Rajiv Gandhi Grameen Vidyutikaran Yojana’ launched?",
    "answerText": 2005
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75802,
    "questionText": " Which place receives fainfall less than 20 cms?",
    "answerText": " Jammu and Kashmir"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75803,
    "questionText": " One astronomical unit is the average distance between which bodies?",
    "answerText": " Earth and the Sun"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75804,
    "questionText": " Who organised a Maratha confederacy against the English leading to the Third Anglo Maratha War?",
    "answerText": " The Peshwa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75805,
    "questionText": " Who was the Governor General when the first Anglo- Burmese was started?",
    "answerText": " Lord Amherst"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75806,
    "questionText": " Which game does Anuja Thakur play?",
    "answerText": " Billiards"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75807,
    "questionText": " What are the ‘Temperate lows’?",
    "answerText": " Sub-polar low pressure belts"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75808,
    "questionText": " At which place will you find maximum sunlight in India December?",
    "answerText": " Kanyakumari"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75809,
    "questionText": " Which was the first synthetic fibre made by man?",
    "answerText": " Nylon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75810,
    "questionText": " The five year term of the President is calculated from which day?",
    "answerText": " The day he assumes charge"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75811,
    "questionText": " Which one of the Chola Kings conquered Ceylon?",
    "answerText": " Rajendra I"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75812,
    "questionText": " Urine of a diabetes patient contains more than average quantity of which thing?",
    "answerText": " Sugar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75813,
    "questionText": " From which fund are the salaries of the Judges of the Supreme Court drawn?",
    "answerText": " Consolidated Fund"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75814,
    "questionText": " The title of whose book translates as my struggle?",
    "answerText": " Adolf Hitler"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75815,
    "questionText": " What was the main occupation of the people of the Indus Valley civilization?",
    "answerText": " Agriculture"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75816,
    "questionText": " The small and marginal farmers will get irrigation facilities through which plan?",
    "answerText": " Ganga Kalyan Yojna"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75817,
    "questionText": " During the reign of which Indian National Congress banned and over 1;20;000 persons were arrested?",
    "answerText": " Lord Willingdon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75818,
    "questionText": " Which is the planet its length of its day and the tilt of its axis are almost identical to those of the earth?",
    "answerText": " Mars"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75819,
    "questionText": " Which is a form of heart disease in which blood supply to the heart is inadequate?",
    "answerText": " Angina"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75820,
    "questionText": " In 1643 Evangalisa Torichelli invented the first what?",
    "answerText": " Barometer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75821,
    "questionText": " During which reign was the Moti Masjid in Delhi built?",
    "answerText": " Aurangzeb"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75822,
    "questionText": " Who built the famous Dilwara temple at Mount Abu in the 13th century?",
    "answerText": " Tejapala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75823,
    "questionText": " The pressure at the bottom of a liquid tank does not depend on which area?",
    "answerText": " Area of the liquid surface"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75824,
    "questionText": " What is myrmecology the study of?",
    "answerText": " Ants"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75825,
    "questionText": " Why is the gas thermometers is more sensitive than the liquid thermometer?",
    "answerText": " Expand more than liquids"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75826,
    "questionText": " At the summer solstice; which latitude will have the longest night?",
    "answerText": " 60°S"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75827,
    "questionText": " When did the last female Alpine ibex disappear in France?",
    "answerText": 2000
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75828,
    "questionText": " How many zones in Indian Railways?",
    "answerText": " Nine (9)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75829,
    "questionText": " In which year Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) was setup in India?",
    "answerText": 1948
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75830,
    "questionText": " Who is the first person to conduct heart transplantation in India?",
    "answerText": " Dr. Venugopal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75831,
    "questionText": " By whom was Agra Fort built?",
    "answerText": " Akbar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75832,
    "questionText": " Who among the following is the first Asian Winner of Nobel Prize?",
    "answerText": " Rabindranath Tagore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75833,
    "questionText": " The Arab conquest of Sind took place in which year?",
    "answerText": " 712 A.D."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75834,
    "questionText": " By whom are the Chairman and members of State Public Service Commission appointed?",
    "answerText": " President"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75835,
    "questionText": " In which veda is the famous Vedic saying “War begins in the minds of men stated?",
    "answerText": " Atharvaveda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75836,
    "questionText": " Who was a great ruler of Kalinga in ancient times?",
    "answerText": " Kharavela"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75837,
    "questionText": " Most of the explosions in mines occur due to the mixing of things?",
    "answerText": " Oxygen with acetylene"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75838,
    "questionText": " Where did India first win the Olympic Hockey gold?",
    "answerText": " Amsterdam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75839,
    "questionText": " What was the ancient name of Bengal?",
    "answerText": " Gauda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75840,
    "questionText": " Which is the most ancient musical instrument?",
    "answerText": " Veena"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75841,
    "questionText": " Which Maratha Peshwa followed the ideal of Hindu Pada-Padshahi?",
    "answerText": " Baji Rao I"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75842,
    "questionText": " The present demographic transition of India is indicative of which thing?",
    "answerText": " Typically increasing urbanisation"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75843,
    "questionText": " The ‘Rediscovery of India’ is written by which author?",
    "answerText": " Meghnad Desai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75844,
    "questionText": " A crossed cheque is one; which can be encashed only at which bank?",
    "answerText": " State Bank of India"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75845,
    "questionText": " In India; in which sector was the co-operative movement initiated?",
    "answerText": " Agricultural credit"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75846,
    "questionText": " Which of the element of group 17 is radioactive?",
    "answerText": " Astatine"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75847,
    "questionText": " Which scientist shared the Nobel Prize in Physics with his son?",
    "answerText": " William Henry Bragg"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75848,
    "questionText": " Kurnool-Cuddapah canal is taken off from which river?",
    "answerText": " Tungabhadra"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75849,
    "questionText": " How is general weather associated with anticyclone?",
    "answerText": " Fine and dry"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75850,
    "questionText": " What are Shield volcanoes?",
    "answerText": " Repeated lava flows"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75851,
    "questionText": " Mughal dynasty was to Bahadur Shah ‘Zafar’ as Lodi dynasty was to which ruler?",
    "answerText": " Ibrahim Lodi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75852,
    "questionText": " In which Union Territory people of the Onge tribe live?",
    "answerText": " Andaman and Nicobar Islands"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75853,
    "questionText": " By which are heredity characters of parent transfered to their offspring?",
    "answerText": " Chromosomes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75854,
    "questionText": " When was ‘Common Market for Eastern and Southern African (COMESA) formed?",
    "answerText": 1994
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75855,
    "questionText": " Which dynasty ruled over India after the invasion of Timur?",
    "answerText": " Sayyid dynasty"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75856,
    "questionText": " By which can the location and energy of an electron in an atom be specified?",
    "answerText": " Quantum numbers"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75857,
    "questionText": " Who presided over the first Buddhist Council held at Rajgriha?",
    "answerText": " Maha Kassapa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75858,
    "questionText": " If you had Tritonopia what would you not see?",
    "answerText": " Colour Blue"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75859,
    "questionText": " Which Bacteria commonly lives in the intestine of human?",
    "answerText": " Escherichia coli"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75860,
    "questionText": " Which ruler is most famous for building a large number of canals for irrigation?",
    "answerText": " Firoz Shah Tughlaq"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75861,
    "questionText": " Where were the war criminals of the II World War put to trial?",
    "answerText": " Peitersburg"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75862,
    "questionText": " In which age the Man passed from the food gathering stage to the food producing stage?",
    "answerText": " Neolithic Age"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75863,
    "questionText": " Which UN body deals with population problem?",
    "answerText": " UNFPA"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75864,
    "questionText": " In Islam what is the third piller of wisdom?",
    "answerText": " Charity - 2.5 % of income (there's 5 in total)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75865,
    "questionText": " Middle ear is not found in snake. Through part do they receive sound?",
    "answerText": " Skin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75866,
    "questionText": " Tradition has it that By whom was Ajatasatru instigated to murder his father?",
    "answerText": " Devadatta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75867,
    "questionText": " Who published the book ‘Origin of species by natural selection in 1859’?",
    "answerText": " Darwin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75868,
    "questionText": " National Research Centre on Plant Biotechnology is situated at which place?",
    "answerText": " New Delhi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75869,
    "questionText": " One horse power is equal to how many watts?",
    "answerText": " 746 watts"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75870,
    "questionText": " Which chemical is used for preserving fruit juices?",
    "answerText": " Sodium benzoate"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75871,
    "questionText": " What is the largest gland in the human body?",
    "answerText": " Liver"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75872,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Deputy Chairman of Planning Commission of India?",
    "answerText": " Shri V. T. Krishnamachari"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75873,
    "questionText": " Which soil formed by the deposition of silt brought by rivers?",
    "answerText": " Alluvial soil"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75874,
    "questionText": " Which are two richest known sources of edible protein?",
    "answerText": " Soy-bean and groundnut"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75875,
    "questionText": " Which is the biggest lake in India?",
    "answerText": " Chilka Lake"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75876,
    "questionText": " If news is broadcast from London at 10:30 AM; at what time it will be heard at Baghdad (450 E)?",
    "answerText": 0.5625
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75877,
    "questionText": " Which mixture is homogeneous?",
    "answerText": " Methanol and water"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75878,
    "questionText": " Conversion of chemical energy into electrical energy occurs in which thing?",
    "answerText": " Battery"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75879,
    "questionText": " What is the middle name of the world class batsman Sachin Tendulkar?",
    "answerText": " Ramesh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75880,
    "questionText": " How is development?",
    "answerText": " Wider than economic growth"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75881,
    "questionText": " Whose successful book include circle of Reason and shadow lines?",
    "answerText": " Amitav Ghosh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75882,
    "questionText": " What about ministry in the event of the resignation or death of the Prime Minister?",
    "answerText": " The Ministry is dissolved"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75883,
    "questionText": " The distance between the earth and the sun is smallest in which month?",
    "answerText": " January"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75884,
    "questionText": " A fan produces a feeling of comfort during hot weather. Why?",
    "answerText": " Our perspiration evaporates rapidly"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75885,
    "questionText": " Which is a warm ocean current?",
    "answerText": " East Australian current"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75886,
    "questionText": " Which rulers began the construction' of the famous Kailasa rock-cut temple at Ellora?",
    "answerText": " Krishna-I"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75887,
    "questionText": " Which was the journalist who refused to accept Padma Bhushan?",
    "answerText": " Arun Shourie"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75888,
    "questionText": " When it is P.M. in Tokyo; what is the time at Panama Canal which is located at 180° W of it?",
    "answerText": " 8.00 A.M."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75889,
    "questionText": " Opium-war was fought between which countries?",
    "answerText": " Britain and Japan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75890,
    "questionText": " With which was Tarapore Committee associated?",
    "answerText": " Fuller capital account convertibility"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75891,
    "questionText": " Michael Jackson was a distinguished personality in which field?",
    "answerText": " Pop music"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75892,
    "questionText": " Rutherford’s scattering experiment related to the size of which thing?",
    "answerText": " Nucleus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75893,
    "questionText": " Which tissue take part in healing the wounds?",
    "answerText": " Epithelium tissue"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75894,
    "questionText": " Which Indian cricketer has bagged a deal with ESPN?",
    "answerText": " Sachin Tendulkar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75895,
    "questionText": " Chlorine acts as a bleaching agent only in the presence of which thing?",
    "answerText": " Moisture"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75896,
    "questionText": " What is the dense mass of small water drops on smoke particles in the lower layers of the atmosphere?",
    "answerText": " Smog"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75897,
    "questionText": " Who was a contemporary of Gautama Buddha?",
    "answerText": " Vardhaman Mahavira"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75898,
    "questionText": " In order of their distances from the Sun; which planet lie between Mars and Uranus?",
    "answerText": " Jupiter and Saturn"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75899,
    "questionText": " On which date the United Nations Organisation came into existence?",
    "answerText": " Oct. 24; 1945"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75900,
    "questionText": " Which is the brightest of all the planets and also known as the Morning Star or the Evening Star?",
    "answerText": " Venus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75901,
    "questionText": " How many players are there on each side in a baseball match?",
    "answerText": 5
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75902,
    "questionText": " With whose reign is the Gandhara school of art associated?",
    "answerText": " Kanishka"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75903,
    "questionText": " Which ruler in India challenged the authority of the Ulemas or Muslim clergy?",
    "answerText": " Alauddin Khilji"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75904,
    "questionText": " Folk painting ‘Madhubani’ is famous in which state?",
    "answerText": " Bihar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75905,
    "questionText": " The ruler which was not invited to join the confederacy to fight against Vijaynagar in the battle of Talikota?",
    "answerText": " Berar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75906,
    "questionText": " The greatest development in the Kushana period was in which field?",
    "answerText": " Art"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75907,
    "questionText": " Krishnadeva Raya wrote a famous work; namely Amuktamalyada; in which language?",
    "answerText": " Telugu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75908,
    "questionText": " Which is the contractile protein muscle?",
    "answerText": " Myosin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75909,
    "questionText": " How much blood does an average adult have in the body?",
    "answerText": " 5-6 litres"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75910,
    "questionText": " What are the brothers Umakant and Ramakant Gundecha?",
    "answerText": " Dhrupad vocalists"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75911,
    "questionText": " Who became the first woman in the world to ski to the North Pole?",
    "answerText": " Ann Banoraft"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75912,
    "questionText": " How many gold medals did P.T. Usha win in the 1986 Seoul Asian Games?",
    "answerText": 4
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75913,
    "questionText": " Where was a Buddhisit council during the reign of Ashoka held?",
    "answerText": " At Pataliputra"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75914,
    "questionText": " What is the principle by which a cooling system (Radiator) in a motor car works?",
    "answerText": " Convection"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75915,
    "questionText": " What was the capital of Ethiopia?",
    "answerText": " Addis Ababa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75916,
    "questionText": " Which rulers fought the fourth Anglo-Mysore in which he was killed?",
    "answerText": " Tipu Sultan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75917,
    "questionText": " Chandragupta Maurya figures prominently in whose book?",
    "answerText": " Vishakhdatta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75918,
    "questionText": " Which are connected by over 1700 km-long BTC oil pipe-line?",
    "answerText": " Caspian sea and Mediterranean sea"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75919,
    "questionText": " The headquarters of International Atomic Energy Agency is located in which city?",
    "answerText": " Vienna"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75920,
    "questionText": " Which Strait separates Africa from Europe?",
    "answerText": " Strait of Gibraltar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75921,
    "questionText": " Which muscle is the strongest of all in the human body?",
    "answerText": " Thigh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75922,
    "questionText": " Which mineral is essential for controling heart beat?",
    "answerText": " Iodine"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75923,
    "questionText": " Who are not protected against inflation?",
    "answerText": " Agricultural farmers"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75924,
    "questionText": " Which an important product is obtained from styles and stigma?",
    "answerText": " Saffron"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75925,
    "questionText": " What is the normal cholesterol level in human blood?",
    "answerText": " 180-200 mg%"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75926,
    "questionText": " Which Element present in largest amount in human body?",
    "answerText": " Oxygen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75927,
    "questionText": " Which is known as the queen of spices?",
    "answerText": " Cardamom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75928,
    "questionText": " Which climatic type suffers change due to shifting of the World’s Pressure Belts?",
    "answerText": " Monsoon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75929,
    "questionText": " During the fermentation of sugar; which enzyme which converts glucose into ethyl alcohol?",
    "answerText": " zymase"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75930,
    "questionText": " What are the atoms of the elements which have same number of neutrons called?",
    "answerText": " Isotones"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75931,
    "questionText": " What is the composition of Nitrolim-a chemical fertilizer?",
    "answerText": " Calcium carbide and nitrogen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75932,
    "questionText": " What was the earlier name of Surinam?",
    "answerText": " Dutch Guyana"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75933,
    "questionText": " The General happiness is the end of the state”; who said this?",
    "answerText": " Bentham"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75934,
    "questionText": " What is saliva in man?",
    "answerText": " Alkaline"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75935,
    "questionText": " After how much time are the elections to Panchayats are to be held?",
    "answerText": " Every five years"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75936,
    "questionText": " Which is the best conductor of electricity?",
    "answerText": " Silve"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75937,
    "questionText": " In whom did the Government of India Act; 1935 vested the residuary power?",
    "answerText": " Governor-General"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75938,
    "questionText": " By whom was Gene first isolated?",
    "answerText": " Hargobind Khurana"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75939,
    "questionText": " With which had the Indus Valley people trade relations?",
    "answerText": " Mesopotamia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75940,
    "questionText": " Who wrote Tughluqnamah?",
    "answerText": " Amir Khusrau"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75941,
    "questionText": " West Bengal shares boundaries with how many foreign countries?",
    "answerText": " Three"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75942,
    "questionText": " When does the South Pole experiences continuous light?",
    "answerText": " At winter solstice"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75943,
    "questionText": " Which organ in animals breaks fat to produce cholesterol?",
    "answerText": " Liver"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75944,
    "questionText": " What is the maximum permissible period between two sessions of a State Legislative Assembly?",
    "answerText": " Six months"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75945,
    "questionText": " Which region in India receives substantial rain during the winter month of January?",
    "answerText": " Punjab"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75946,
    "questionText": " Viticulture is the growing of what plants?",
    "answerText": " Vines"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75947,
    "questionText": " ‘Chinaman’ refers to which game?",
    "answerText": " Cricket"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75948,
    "questionText": " On which basis Montague-Chelmsford Report formed?",
    "answerText": " The Government of India Act; 1919"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75949,
    "questionText": " The religious text Mishna comes from which religion?",
    "answerText": " Judaism"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75950,
    "questionText": " Where was the Arya Samaj setup for the first time in 1875?",
    "answerText": " Bombay"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75951,
    "questionText": " When the Vice-President acts as President he gets the emoluments of which post?",
    "answerText": " President"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75952,
    "questionText": " What is an upper air wind system with very high velocities in certain parts of the atmosphere?",
    "answerText": " Jet stream"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75953,
    "questionText": " Which part of human brain is the regulating centre for swallowing and vomiting?",
    "answerText": " Medulla oblongata"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75954,
    "questionText": " Who created Tarzan (all names) in 1914?",
    "answerText": " Edgar Rice Burroughs"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75955,
    "questionText": " First International Telephone line was started between Mumbai and London in?",
    "answerText": 1870
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75956,
    "questionText": " Which is the largest phylum in the animal kingdom in respect of number of species?",
    "answerText": " Arthropoda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75957,
    "questionText": " Which river does not form any delta at its mouth?",
    "answerText": " Tapti & Narmada"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75958,
    "questionText": " By whom was word Adivasi was used for the first time to refer to the tribal people?",
    "answerText": " Thakkar Bappa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75959,
    "questionText": " EI Nino current appears along the coast of which country?",
    "answerText": " Peru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75960,
    "questionText": " What is the green color of plants produced from organelles?",
    "answerText": " Chloroplasts"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75961,
    "questionText": " Malaria parasite and Amoeba are grouped under?",
    "answerText": " Protozoa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75962,
    "questionText": " Who is the founder of world Economic Forum?",
    "answerText": " Klaus Schwab"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75963,
    "questionText": " Which city is known for silk wearing industry?",
    "answerText": " Kanchepuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75964,
    "questionText": " To which UN organ; does the Security Council send its annual report?",
    "answerText": " General Assembly"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75965,
    "questionText": " Who has scored the most runs in a one day International Cricket innings?",
    "answerText": " Virendra Sehwag"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75966,
    "questionText": " ‘IC chips’ for computers are usually made of which metal?",
    "answerText": " Silicon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75967,
    "questionText": " Which is the planet nearest to the earth?",
    "answerText": " Mercury"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75968,
    "questionText": " Who was nicknames The desert Fox?",
    "answerText": " Erwin Rommel"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75969,
    "questionText": " Cirrhosis is a disease that affects which organ?",
    "answerText": " Liver"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75970,
    "questionText": " What work is work done in moving a positive charge on an equipotential surface?",
    "answerText": " Zero"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75971,
    "questionText": " Mostly in which region do Earthquakes and volcanoes occur?",
    "answerText": " Folded and faulted region"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75972,
    "questionText": " Which are the most important commercial forests of India?",
    "answerText": " Tropical deciduous"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75973,
    "questionText": " What is the interrelated food chains in an ecological community?",
    "answerText": " Food Web"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75974,
    "questionText": " Which was the king generally considered to be the greatest ruler of Kashmir in the 15th century?",
    "answerText": " Zain-ul-Abidin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75975,
    "questionText": " How much protein a working woman must intake everyday?",
    "answerText": " 45 g"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75976,
    "questionText": " Under which climatic conditions do the laterite soils develop?",
    "answerText": " Wet tropical climate"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75977,
    "questionText": " Department of Official Language (Raj Bhasha Vibhag) comes under which Ministries?",
    "answerText": " Ministry of Home Affairs"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75978,
    "questionText": " Which is the variety of coal in which the deposit contains recognisable traces of the original plant material?",
    "answerText": " Peat"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75979,
    "questionText": " Where are the headquarters of the Organization of the Islamic Conference (OIC) located?",
    "answerText": " Jeddah"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75980,
    "questionText": " Which place ranks second among the coldest places in the world?",
    "answerText": " Dras (Jammu and Kashmir)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75981,
    "questionText": " The ODI Player of the Year 2012’ Award was given by ICC to which India cricketer?",
    "answerText": " Virat Kohli"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75982,
    "questionText": " To which do the residuary powers of legislation in case of Jammu and Kashmir belong?",
    "answerText": " The State Legislature"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75983,
    "questionText": " By whom was the Doctrine of Lapse introduced?",
    "answerText": " Lord Dalhousie"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75984,
    "questionText": " Which pair of States is the leading producer of tobacco in India?",
    "answerText": " Andhra Pradesh and Gujarat"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75985,
    "questionText": " Which crop would be preferred for sowing in order to enrich the soil with nitrogen?",
    "answerText": " Gram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75986,
    "questionText": " Who united all the Sikhs and founded a kingdom in the Punjab?",
    "answerText": " Maharaja Ranjit Singh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75987,
    "questionText": " On which date the Indians celebrated the independence Day for the first time?",
    "answerText": " January 26; 1930"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75988,
    "questionText": " In which ocean is Diamantina Trench situated?",
    "answerText": " Indian Ocean"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75989,
    "questionText": " Who proposed the Preamble before the Drafting Committee of the Constitution?",
    "answerText": " Jawaharlal Nehru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75990,
    "questionText": " During the reign of which dynasty did Kalidasa flourish?",
    "answerText": " Guptas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75991,
    "questionText": " Which was the official language of Gupta period?",
    "answerText": " Sanskrit"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75992,
    "questionText": " Which case does stagflation imply?",
    "answerText": " Recession plus inflation"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75993,
    "questionText": " Which nuclear particles responsible for holding all nucleons together?",
    "answerText": " Mesons"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75994,
    "questionText": " The United Nations declared 2013 as which International Year?",
    "answerText": " Quinoa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75995,
    "questionText": " The ‘Misl’ of which Ranjit Singh was the leader?",
    "answerText": " Sukerchakia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75996,
    "questionText": " A small weight is put on the pressure cooker. It increases the pressure of the steam. Why?",
    "answerText": " Area of contact is small"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75997,
    "questionText": " Which is the highest lake above the sea level in the world?",
    "answerText": " Lake Titicaca"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75998,
    "questionText": " Terms of economics; which recession occurring two times with a small gap in between?",
    "answerText": " Deep Recession"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 75999,
    "questionText": " The highest peak of the Himalayas in India is in which state?",
    "answerText": " Sikkim"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 76000,
    "questionText": " Which organizations agency is involved in drafting the Union Budget of India?",
    "answerText": " Administrative Ministries only"
  }
]